Soon | NTU: Good evening, everyone.
germayne: Okay, hello, hello everyone. Hi, hi. Nice to see you guys.
germayne: Again, Hope you guys are… energized. For tonight, we have some catch-up to do.
germayne: You guys can hear me, right? Can you guys hear me?
germayne: Am I audio gone? I'm audio bad.
Soon | NTU: Yes, Kenya.
J Mohan: Yep, yep.
germayne: Okay, so I think… I think we will start… we'll start promptly on time.
germayne: about 7.05. What I'll do is I'll just take 5 minutes
germayne: I'll take 5 minutes to just quickly… Give a quick…
germayne: summary of what we've done on Tuesday. Then, I think what I will do is I'll hand over to
germayne: Soon, right? Soon, we will add Note 1, right? Correct?
Soon | NTU: Yes, we have a computer number one.
Soon | NTU: And then we'll continue with 2, 3, and… boring today.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Home spend is my… is my…
germayne: Why is my computer lagging? You guys are okay, right? Is it only on my side?
AU YANG TAR ben: We're okay.
germayne: You guys are okay, right?
Soon | NTU: Jamie, I will, I'll cover.
germayne: get paid.
Soon | NTU: 2 and 3 first.
Soon | NTU: Part 4, do you want me to do it after the Part 3, or we will do it on Saturday?
germayne: No, I, I will, I will, I will cover the theory first.
Soon | NTU: Okay, yeah, okay, I'll do about 2 and 3 first.
germayne: Okay, I think… I think my… my computer might be lagging.
germayne: So, okay, I think, I think let me… I think in the interest of time.
germayne: what will happen is, I will hand over to Sun first, and I'll restart my computer. It's just lagging. I'm not sure what is happening on my side.
germayne: So…
Soon | NTU: You guys have…
germayne: I'm still audible.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, 50.
germayne: Okay, okay, I'll hand over to… I'll hand over to Sun first. I'll log back in again. Yeah, I'll start my conversation.
germayne: Computer.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Okay, good evening. So, okay, while this, Chomaine is,
Soon | NTU: getting back online. So, let's, to do a quick recap of, not so much on the, the, the, the source, the slide content, okay, but…
Soon | NTU: for me, just go through what we have covered in the notebook, to be the notebook, right? So, basically, in part one, what we have gone through.
Soon | NTU: so-called the essential pre-processing steps, which usually we need to take, right? Cleansing, patch up missing data, and also a lot of other things, right? So, some of the things are very important, because if you do not prepare your data
Soon | NTU: sufficient enough for the machine learning model training, okay? So, you would not be able to get the optimal results, right, even after you have done lots of training, right? Because,
Soon | NTU: machine learning training depends a lot on the mathematics, okay? So if the numbers are not of a good quality.
Soon | NTU: Right? Then you will not get optimal result in the end, right? So what we have gone through in the…
Soon | NTU: Part 1.
Soon | NTU: what we've gone through in Part 1 of the…
Soon | NTU: out of the four parts, right, of the notebook, is we have seen, the one very important, preprocessing step, okay, for categorical value is to encode the
Soon | NTU: text, okay? Categorical variables are nothing but just something that have text content, right, or the ABC, but they are not numbers, okay? So, in order to prepare this data for machine learning training, we have to convert it into numbers. So, there are two techniques.
Soon | NTU: available. One is called the label encoding, and another one is called a one-hot encoding. So, in label encoding.
Soon | NTU: Basically, we convert that text into…
Soon | NTU: 0, 1, 2, 3, and 4, depending on how many unique values they are originally in the column.
Soon | NTU: Right, so in this case, we have tree value, so the max we have is up to 2.
Soon | NTU: Right? With red being the last, I would say the last number, because alphabetically, blue is arranged first, it come before green.
Soon | NTU: And then red, right? The R is the last one in the…
Soon | NTU: 26th alphabet, right? So, that is for labor encoding, but for one-hot encoding, the second method of converting categorical variable into number is to use this
Soon | NTU: get dummy in Pandas.
Soon | NTU: Right, we convert all this, the original color into
Soon | NTU: three additional columns like this. So all these things is done automatically for you, be it you use a PyPenders approach or the scikit-learned approach, okay? Because this library understands that you are going to drop the original categorical column
Soon | NTU: Before the training, okay? So it automatically do it for you.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: So…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that is the, conversion, the output line, okay? So, why we do not want to, use the pandas way of encoding the value is because
Soon | NTU: After you have converting all these to… on how encoding.
Soon | NTU: your original column is lost, okay? So I remember, Tuesday, someone asked, you know, what happened to the original value, okay? So this is where, as much as possible, right, when you're doing those serious stuff on machine learning training, we are trying to use the scikit-learn to do our encoding, right? So.
Soon | NTU: And Scikit-Loan can also do the same, both label encoding and one-haul encoding, okay, by importing the necessary library, right? And then, in the end, you will still get the same results, okay? But…
Soon | NTU: Yes, even though the final result will show the original color column is gone, but the original value of this color column are stored in the one hot encoder, which I've shown it to you, right? How to display the
Soon | NTU: The original value, right, is embedded in this encoder variable.
Soon | NTU: Ring.
Soon | NTU: you can… Safe keep you somewhere, you know, in your… in your… your… Cool, yeah.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that is for categorical variable, but how about preparing numerical variable? Okay, so we have gone through a few techniques of scaling, meaning to change the scale, numerical scale of the different feature.
Soon | NTU: so that they are comparable, right? So during training, the machine learning model, okay, will not get some
Soon | NTU: just look at the, predominant feature, okay, especially when one of the features have very large numbers, okay? Large number compared with small number, usually we look at only the large number, right? Mathematically, you know the results, right?
Soon | NTU: So… So, scaling, we have standardization.
Soon | NTU: scaling the data to a mean of 0 and standard deviation of 1, okay? And likewise, we also have a using a mean-max scaling, and depending on the nature of your data, right, so one of the decisions is, are there any outlier?
Soon | NTU: Okay, or are there any, reasons for you to use min-max scaling? But…
Soon | NTU: Usually, we'll use a standard scaler, right, unless, it is Also.
Soon | NTU: okay to use the MingMex scaling, yeah?
Soon | NTU: And for normalization, usually it is more applicable to…
Soon | NTU: the, NLP, okay, where we are not looking at scaling the Number…
Soon | NTU: column-wise, but we are doing it row-wise. Okay, so that one, we will go in through the, in detail of the,
Soon | NTU: Normalization, okay, when we look at this,
Soon | NTU: cosine similarity, right? This is one of the concepts in the large… this is a natural language processing in Module 3.9.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we will not, go into the detail because soft key.
Soon | NTU: I think it would be quite difficult for us to relate, you know, how we use this in the reality, right? Now, handling missing value, of course, there are many, many ways of doing that, right? So, for numbers, we can
Soon | NTU: Using mainly to strategy.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so either you, remove the… Column, or remove the row.
Soon | NTU: That have missing value.
Soon | NTU: Otherwise, you can choose to impute. Okay, impute is to backfill, fill in the blank, you know? Whichever cell you see that is a none.
Soon | NTU: You just…
Soon | NTU: fill in something, okay? So in, last week, last, session, we have seen how we backfilled it with, mean, okay? Mean of the existing number, okay? So this is what we get, and then…
Soon | NTU: Right. And then the next… The last part of the, part one, we have gone through
Soon | NTU: A bit of showing you how to
Soon | NTU: assess the performance of the classification model, okay? In the case of part one, we have shown logistic regression, okay? And we have
Soon | NTU: Use some of these.
Soon | NTU: performance… performance metrics. Okay, so there are a lot for classification, model.
Soon | NTU: They also have, different classification, performance metrics for evaluating the performance of regression model. Okay, so classification is
Soon | NTU: having its own performance metrics. Namely.
Soon | NTU: Confusion metrics, accuracy, precision, Recall, and epon score.
Soon | NTU: Right? So, depending on the use case that you have, right, you may want to weigh, let's say, for example, your force positive
Soon | NTU: More than y'all.
Soon | NTU: False negative, okay, because your… Penalty, okay, if you make a wrong decision on your Force positive is more…
Soon | NTU: Then you will have to focus more on the, precision score, okay? On the other hand, if you
Soon | NTU: need to pay a high price for making a wrong decision on the false negative, then you have to make sure your recall score is very, very high, alright?
Soon | NTU: Okay, because decision… precision does not measure how much you predicted.
Soon | NTU: negatively, whether you're right or wrong, you will not count that into the precision score, okay? So, based on the… your use case, we will have to select the
Soon | NTU: performance metrics accordingly. Okay, so this is what we have gone through, right? And also, we have, gone through some of the,
Soon | NTU: Confusion metrics.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: And there is a bit of an overlap between the last part of the Part 1 Jupyter Notebook, okay, and the beginning part of the Part 2 Jupyter Notebooks.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, okay, so for this part two, again, It is…
Soon | NTU: If I were to show you…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so it is actually the same as this part, okay? So, I will just quickly go through.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we basically, we are… Generating some syntactic data, so… We focus on,
Soon | NTU: explaining to you the concept first, rather than focusing on the, real-life data set, right? So, just, using
Soon | NTU: 1,000 samples. 1,000 points.
Soon | NTU: for illustration, each of these points will be 20 columns, okay? And then… After training.
Soon | NTU: We'll get the…
Soon | NTU: score as before. Okay, let me run it. We have done it already, on the Tuesday, but I will just go through again.
Soon | NTU: Just to show you.
Soon | NTU: Right? And then we have gone through this accuracy…
Soon | NTU: or it's confusion metric, and so on, okay? All these are only applicable When you are…
Soon | NTU: Creating, training a classification model, right?
Soon | NTU: Regression model will not look at all this.
Soon | NTU: Okay? Because regression model, we only predict numbers, right? Prediction means
Soon | NTU: You'd only be reliable if the error is small.
Soon | NTU: prediction error is not. So this is not relevant to the regression model.
Soon | NTU: Okay, let me quickly go through.
Soon | NTU: Okay, no.
Soon | NTU: On Tuesday, we have also gone through this concept of an ROC curve.
Soon | NTU: And, area under the curve. Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: Jamin has explained, or shared with you, right, for ROC curve, so basically, we have gone through all the threshold, you know the threshold.
Soon | NTU: Logistic regression, default threshold is 0.51.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we go through all the different threshold forms, 0.1, 2, 0.2, and so on, all the way until 1, and then we plot the different
Soon | NTU: So-called the, true… Possibly.
Soon | NTU: on the vertical axis, and then the force positive rate on the horizontal axis, okay? So, you will get a curve like this.
Soon | NTU: For each of the models that you have.
Soon | NTU: Training.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: So… The conclusion is that If you have a line like this.
Soon | NTU: the area is quite big, right? Under the curve. The max is… you have an area here.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: Then you have an AUC equal to 1.
Soon | NTU: Okay, of course, that is an ideal situation, but in the real worst scenario, we usually have somewhere in between, okay? We will not like to see our model after training
Soon | NTU: hours of training, okay, to end up to be a straight line like this, diagonal, okay? Because this is our…
Soon | NTU: random classifier.
Soon | NTU: So, a classifier without training, so it just randomly gets positive, negative, positive, negative. So, in the end, it's 50-50 chance of getting the result correct.
Soon | NTU: Right? So if your model is like this so much, well, you don't…
Soon | NTU: discard the model, okay? Don't need to spend time, training, okay? So, of course.
Soon | NTU: If there is potential in the model, we will try to fine-tune it, right? Getting the optimal hyperparameter so that it gives you
Soon | NTU: A better, performance game.
Soon | NTU: And that is why we will go through this hyperparameter tuning, okay, after this, Part 2 and 3.
Soon | NTU: Great.
Soon | NTU: So… Okay, so we'll go through the codes.
Soon | NTU: Right, so this is the, the new…
Soon | NTU: It's a continuation of a part one, right? So, we have already trained our logistic regression model, right?
Soon | NTU: In part one, okay? So now we are continuing to see Based on this, metrics.
Soon | NTU: ist them.
Soon | NTU: model really good, right? Because if you look at the metrics, 0.9… above 0.9, fine, okay? So what is it… does it mean? Is it very, very good? Okay, so why not we look at the performance of this logistic model after training, visually on the graph, okay? So we can see that
Soon | NTU: This is our logistic regression after training, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, they're still very close to this one here.
Soon | NTU: Okay, 1, and he has an area under the curve equal to 0.98, right, which is the same as what we have,
Soon | NTU: obtain, and here.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: I think part one.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is 0.98.
Soon | NTU: the one I ate, and this is…
Soon | NTU: how the ROC of the logistic regression model looks like.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so is 0.98 a very good number?
Soon | NTU: Is it a very good number?
Soon | NTU: Is the performance of this model very good?
Soon | NTU: acceptable.
Soon | NTU: or you have confidence to roll out in the production environment with an AUC of 0.98.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Do we consider overfit?
Soon | NTU: Okay, that's a very good, question. Okay, yes, I think you, you, you're right in saying, okay, so we have to really
Soon | NTU: We really test it out, right? Because given our…
Soon | NTU: Data size is only 1,000 points.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we cannot quickly draw our conclusion that, oh, this is a very good model, okay? It so happened that our sample, you know, sampling concept come into play, okay? So, the 1,000 sample that we have drawn from the population happened to be very good data.
Soon | NTU: Okay? So, what have…
Soon | NTU: When I make a mistake, like, what this, Jermaine Wright mentioned? This time is good.
Soon | NTU: How about, next sample, it may give you a very lousy score.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so you have to ensure that quite a lot of other factors are taken into consideration.
Soon | NTU: Especially your dataset size. 1000 on logistic regression, I think with a feature of 20,
Soon | NTU: Okay, yes, you are right in saying is it Chie Ching?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so it is a very good, question, okay?
Soon | NTU: it may be overfitting. With only 1,000 rows, you have 20 features with 20 columns. Okay, so that is not really sufficient.
Soon | NTU: For us to conclude that the model is performing well.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: Usually, there's a… Depending on the complexity of the model, there is some kind of a guideline.
Soon | NTU: Of course, if you have 1 to 50,
Soon | NTU: Every feature you have, you must have sufficient number of rows
Soon | NTU: To support, okay, still learning of your machine.
Soon | NTU: the machine learning model training. Otherwise, the machine learning model won't be able to identify whether you have
Soon | NTU: Sufficient time for it to look at the pattern in each of the columns.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… Good question.
Soon | NTU: So, we have…
Soon | NTU: plotted our ROseeker.
Soon | NTU: And then, for the regression metrics, I'll leave it to, Jermaine to complete the regression model, the section, okay, before we go into the detail of part two. So, let's,
Soon | NTU: Remember, we need to go through this.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we will not cover this.
Soon | NTU: Okay. Now, for part three, this,
Soon | NTU: Any question from anyone at this point in time?
Soon | NTU: Am I too fast?
Soon | NTU: Or am I too slow?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so if you… want me to… any question, again, so feel free to stop me, right? So…
Soon | NTU: Right, for part three, We have, this…
Soon | NTU: use case, again, using the Titanic dataset.
Soon | NTU: I would say this is, very exciting, okay, so it's a very good
Soon | NTU: A very popular dataset for you to
Soon | NTU: Test out all those concepts that you have learned.
Soon | NTU: Okay, in the previous session, okay? So…
Soon | NTU: Now, basically, this, dataset is…
Soon | NTU: a built-in data set of the Seabourne library.
Soon | NTU: G.
Soon | NTU: SeaWorld Library have a lot of other built-in datasets, right? So, this dynamic dataset is the one that we use.
Soon | NTU: To show you, you know, to…
Soon | NTU: I'll explain to you the different kind of concepts that we have learned, yeah? So… this…
Soon | NTU: The tool library that we need to import… okay, let me check.
Soon | NTU: Okay, let me run the cell one by one.
Soon | NTU: Okay? And the Titanic dataset is one of the built-in datasets. There are a lot of other
Soon | NTU: built-in dataset of a Seabond, so you can always, look at.
Soon | NTU: the built-in data set, right?
Soon | NTU: Thing is this, get data set names, okay? So, print it out, and you…
Soon | NTU: Should be able to catch all this.
Soon | NTU: Right? So Titanic is only one of them, right? If you have time, feel free to explore all these, datasets. I think it would be very interesting, okay, for you to explore the different dataset, because each type of dataset will have its own property, own attribute, okay? Some are very…
Soon | NTU: Balance, some imbalanced data set. So, for you to test out which are the metrics you should use to evaluate the respective
Soon | NTU: Dataset or the model after training.
Soon | NTU: So, it is a very good exercise, okay? So, for this Titanic dataset, let's see what the first 5 rows contain.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so usually we… Very good exploratory, kind of,
Soon | NTU: step for you to take a look at the first 5 rows. By default, it's the first 5 rows. You can always expand it if you are curiously, what about the next 20 rows, right?
Soon | NTU: So, this… We'll give you an idea of whether you have a Any missing data?
Soon | NTU: Okay, what are the data type? Okay, so in this Jupyter notebook, in VS Code, right, it gives us some kind of a clue as to the data type of each of these columns, right? Hex is a number.
Soon | NTU: Numeric, A is an alphanumeric, and so on.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: I think there's one for categorical.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is categorical.
Soon | NTU: Right. So, the head will tell you
Soon | NTU: Whether the columns, have a… a name?
Soon | NTU: Like, whether they are of the correct data type, and so on, okay, just to see from the data ID or what kind of data you have imported, okay?
Soon | NTU: And then, of course, there will be some kind of, a check, quick check, on whether your data set is balanced. So, survive is your labor column, okay? So, during training.
Soon | NTU: This is the model answer you are telling your machine learning model, okay, to predict whether is it correct or not.
Soon | NTU: you have to look at your survivor… survive column, which contains either a 0 or 1. Now, for 0, they're all together 5, 4, 9,
Soon | NTU: Rule?
Soon | NTU: And for survive, One is… 3, 4, 8.
Soon | NTU: For two rows.
Soon | NTU: So, a total of… Okay? A total of 891 rows.
Soon | NTU: So, this shape will tell you number of row.
Soon | NTU: And we'll call them.
Soon | NTU: So, is this a balanced dataset?
Soon | NTU: Do you think this is a balanced dataset?
Soon | NTU: did I miss the question, Jiaqing?
Soon | NTU: You mean use the previously trained logistic regression? Okay, so we are going to retrain a new regression model, logistic regression model, for this dataset. Okay, so whatever we have done is the…
Soon | NTU: we only… focusing on learning the confusion metrics, all the different kind of metrics, okay? But for this one.
Soon | NTU: Yes, we are still creating the same logistical question, but it's a new copy.
Soon | NTU: for this Titanic dataset, right? It's totally different, huh?
Soon | NTU: So, now, based on this number, It is slightly, unbalanced.
Soon | NTU: In that, we have more I think it's a… it's a tragic one. Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: More people did not survive then.
Soon | NTU: People who survive, right?
Soon | NTU: So we have almost, 60 or… 65%, yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Right? But in this case, the… let's say for Titanic, I just realized that, you know, let's say this… let's say this is the total, all the… all the people that are on Titanic, then this, the event is in balance, you can't do anything about it, right? I mean, it's like… oh, I mean, the person… the people on the ship.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: die and leave. It's all imbalanced, man. There's nothing you can do about it.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so there is nothing we can do with the imbalanced data set. Okay, so the only thing we can do is, when we split the data, we have to be mindful
Soon | NTU: We have to use this concept called stratify.
Soon | NTU: Okay, technique. Okay, when we speed, we also need to ensure that the proportion of the
Soon | NTU: People survived versus not surviving is also the same as the original data set.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: Yeah, okay, so this is something we can do. Okay, I know people have already…
Soon | NTU: die, pass away, but I think in terms of speeding data, we still can tell the mathematically, right.
Soon | NTU: SlackyLearn, if you speed the data, please ensure that your 65 and 35 proportion still in my training data.
Soon | NTU: And also the test data.
Soon | NTU: You don't speak randomly so that your train data happen to have 100% people who survived.
Soon | NTU: Or not survive. And vice versa.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is something we can do if we…
Soon | NTU: have some knowledge of our data set. Oh, this is an imbalanced dataset, then we will follow with doing something extra during our
Soon | NTU: Preparation, as well as a training lah.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so it doesn't mean that, you know, we cannot do anything about it.
Soon | NTU: yes, yes, whoever has already passed on, you know, we can't do anything, but I think in terms of the… whether the dataset is balanced or not, we… this is a very good, hint to us whether we still need to do some stratified strategy or not during our sampling, techniques.
Soon | NTU: even sampling techniques, right, in Study 6. We also have this concept of sampling
Soon | NTU: Sampling techniques… certified sampling is one of the sampling techniques in 36.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Okay, thank you for your question, Noel.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… We understand there's some kind of a slight imbalance in our dataset, and how about
Soon | NTU: Any missing data?
Soon | NTU: So this is…
Soon | NTU: Okay, if you see a red dot, then this is a breakpoint. Okay, so I don't want to set any breakpoint, okay? So this is NASUM is a very good command to look at your data set, you know, which other columns have missing value, and how many?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so let me show everything.
Soon | NTU: So, in this… output, you know, each column, right? A lot of people…
Soon | NTU: I do not know how old they are, right?
Soon | NTU: And two of the road have, missing and bunk.
Soon | NTU: When did they monitor the… Titanic, okay, and also this deck.
Soon | NTU: Maybe the… the deck, the class. Okay, so this is, and also the Embark Town.
Soon | NTU: Another column to indicate where they actually embark on the ship.
Soon | NTU: Right?
Soon | NTU: So now you know there are actually four columns, right, having missing value.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so let's continue with our feature selection and splitting. Okay, so this is the…
Soon | NTU: Very important part, okay? So, when it comes to feature selection and splitting, right, which are the columns that you select for training your model, okay, that is…
Soon | NTU: very important, okay, when you are doing your, your ego, Which,
Soon | NTU: We will be brief this Saturday, right? There will be a lot of decision that you need to make out of so many columns. Likely that there will be a lot of columns for you to choose from. Some of them are meaningful.
Soon | NTU: Right. Some of them are actually not very informative, okay? If you include them, you'll have a lot of noise in your regression model.
Soon | NTU: The new regression, we're gonna build the…
Soon | NTU: But I think the approach is the same. The choice of the feature is very important, right? So, we have the feature selected, only 7. So, we just make the dataset simple, okay? We do not want to make use of the 15 column, okay? That will make the whole thing very complicated, right? We have chosen.
Soon | NTU: 7 column. So, target.
Soon | NTU: Column is survive.
Soon | NTU: So this is a logistical question. So your survive column can only have two values, 0 and 1. 0 for not survive.
Soon | NTU: One is the Y. So we prepare the X and the Y,
Soon | NTU: Like this. Now, just take note of the naming convention, already. So, usually for our X, Right.
Soon | NTU: We use uppercase for our target variable, we use lowercase.
Soon | NTU: whether training or testing, right? We use uppercase for feature, lowercase for target, okay? So this is a very…
Soon | NTU: high-level summary. Again, you can look at this.
Soon | NTU: Okay, let me make it smaller.
Soon | NTU: Okay, since this is what we are going to do. So, we will go through a lot of, you know.
Soon | NTU: Patching missing value.
Soon | NTU: Right? On the left-hand side, we have numerical feature, numerical column. On the right-hand side, we have categorical feature. So, both sides will have to go through the same thing, patching missing value, using imputation.
Soon | NTU: We did not choose to remove them. We choose to retain everything, and then…
Soon | NTU: impute them with some number. In the case of number, it's… Numerical feature is median.
Soon | NTU: For categorical feature, we impute it with more.
Soon | NTU: most frequently awkward number, the value, okay? And then for number, we go through standard scaling.
Soon | NTU: Right? So we change all the numeric column to a comparable numeric scale.
Soon | NTU: With a mean of 0 and standard deviation of 1.
Soon | NTU: Right, so all the numbers will be very small. So there will be negative number, or C number, but they are all very close to zero.
Soon | NTU: And then for categorical Feature, We'll use one hot encoding on this three columns.
Soon | NTU: Gain.
Soon | NTU: To change them into… 0 and 1.
Soon | NTU: Right? All binary values.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But in this case, right, in this case, let's assume that this Titanic is the real, the real, real case, I'm assuming, then, like, shouldn't we, like, impute on, on things like age, right? Wouldn't it be, like, a bit,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: a bit wrong on our side to do it. I mean, like, why do you want to do… I mean, it's empty, it's empty, why do you need to…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: When you draw the age, verbal diary, we don't know what age they are, do we need to really improve age?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, like, if we don't have… we don't… you mean, like, if we don't do the age in there, we can't, we can't carry on the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the prediction.
Soon | NTU: Now, this prediction, right, I know we cannot go back to the history lah, like, go back to the past, okay? So.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I'm thinking, like, in this case, let's say we are dealing with data that is, like, you know, quite sensitive, then if we were to do, like, you know, do things on AI, would it be, like.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Introducing a lot of, unknowns that we shouldn't even bother… shouldn't even start with in the first place.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, just… It's a wrong topic, though.
Soon | NTU: A very good, reference data set, right? Well, because if you have information like this, okay, so…
Soon | NTU: if you don't talk about Titanic dataset, so maybe we talk about Irish dataset, maybe it's still useful, but because this is a historical.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, so, so I'm thinking, like, if there's some… if you are dealing with some data, like, it's, like, really… I mean, if it's in anime, it's okay, but it's dealing some… let's say we are dealing with very sensitive data, like, name, like, maybe Titanic, people already die, like, whatever, you know, whatever it is.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Then, I mean, from an ethical point of view, like,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Like, should we do… should we do impute and, you know, remove and things like that? I mean, I don't know, I'm not sure, I just… I'm just thinking out loud, that's all. Yeah, yeah. Man, I don't spell the answer.
Soon | NTU: That's what we say, it's a toy machine learning concept, right? Yeah, correct. Yes, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: And I'm just thinking, like, in real life, if we see things like that, then what should we do, should we just… just…
Soon | NTU: Now, will you be, let's say,
Soon | NTU: Okay, maybe not North Thomas. Let's say, I'm going to take this ferry, And start cruise, yeah.
Soon | NTU: But I think the size of the ship looks like titanic. Then, I would look at his classification, then I say, hey, should I buy a first class?
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: The chance of survival? Is it the highest? Yes, I think the chance of survival, in the first class is highest.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so it will make you think twice whether you should spend only a bit for,
Soon | NTU: you know, the country ticket, right? You'll definitely, maybe.
Soon | NTU: A tendency is to pay a bit more for first-class ticket.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so it may help you in that case, right, Noel?
Soon | NTU: Yeah, but I think for a testing of this kind of classification model, and training, and the different kind of technique for
Soon | NTU: cleaning missing data, and also the encoding. I think this is a very good, data set.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Right.
Soon | NTU: As the SK learner, Weather.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Agree. I mean, I agree with you.
Hitesh shah: Why are we imputing sex? There were no missing values for sex, so I just wanted to understand.
Soon | NTU: Yeah?
Hitesh shah: So there are no missing values for sex in the database.
Hitesh shah: So, why are we imputing? So, then what will happen if you're imputing for sex? There's nothing…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Very soft.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, so…
Soon | NTU: Of course, we have already gone through the previous few steps, right? Whether there's a need for imputation or not. Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: Don't look at, oh, Titanic dataset, assuming that this is some kind of a toy dataset useful, right, for our learning purpose, right? So, if we have missing value.
Soon | NTU: Of course, we have to go through all this, right? And then one coding, right? Otherwise.
Soon | NTU: We may not need to build our pipeline if our dataset come to us is perfect.
Soon | NTU: Right? Like, this diabetes dataset.
Soon | NTU: It is perfect, everything is scaled, all numeric, we don't even have to do all this.
Soon | NTU: Then there's no need to do any pipeline, don't have a complicated workflow to train our model.
Hitesh shah: Can we, assuming, assuming there is, for some data set, say, sex was missing.
Hitesh shah: Say, for out of 1,000 records, 400 records was missing. And the ratio in the 900 were… for male and female was, say, 45-55.
Hitesh shah: Can we impute based on that ratio as male and female, or we have to put a mode only, so then everything, everyone will become male?
Hitesh shah: Is that a way we can impute, or…
Soon | NTU: Okay, sometimes when you impute, right, you really have to maybe look at what you're trying to impute.
Soon | NTU: Okay, as you say, if the gender is missing, so where is it to impute?
Soon | NTU: Can we assume that, you know, the person with a missing gender is a male?
Soon | NTU: Cannot, right?
Hitesh shah: Yeah, but if you're imputing mode, that means it will impute mail for all the 100,
Soon | NTU: In this case, we have checked that the gender is not a problem, right?
Soon | NTU: Yeah, there's no problem.
Soon | NTU: Okay, probably with age, there's a problem, right? But we have already catered for that.
Soon | NTU: Right. H…
Hitesh shah: EMBA?
Soon | NTU: We did not choose this embarkedown, so it's fine. So our imputation is already taken care of all those columns with missing value.
Soon | NTU: Right, this is the… When we're missing value.
germayne: So maybe, do you want me to have you… I'll just have you elaborate.
germayne: I think… I think, Hitesh, to… to explain your answer, and I think before, I think on Tuesday, somebody asked something similar, right?
germayne: You are being taught the… the specific library method to do imputation.
germayne: If, let's say, you find that the imputation doesn't work.
germayne: Then what do you think is the answer?
germayne: They reteach you in the course to say that
germayne: you can only use the simple imputor from SKLN to do imputation. Can you do any… can you manually do the change? Hitesh, why don't you answer this?
germayne: You can, right?
germayne: Exactly, exactly. So, the point here is that you're not constrained… the pipeline, right, the SKLens pipeline, if it doesn't fit your use case, don't use it. Because, let's say, in my case, I hardly use this except in
germayne: theoretical class. Like, I don't see a need for my use case, but if you have a use case where the function fits.
germayne: Then, perfect. I think somebody asked on… on… on Tuesday about the same for the one-hot encoding. Hey, oh, sorry, I believe it's for labor encoding. Hey, you know, maybe I want male to be 1, I want female to be… to be 2,
germayne: I want, you know, if let's say you want to do that transformation, you can feel free not to use a library, just basically do a left join. If you have a mapping with all the variables, you can just manipulate the data. I mean.
germayne: the… the point is that Module… I believe in Module 1, you guys already have the… I mean, this is a programming language, right?
germayne: You essentially can use anything that you deem fit. If the function doesn't work, you write your own function.
germayne: So, I think the question here is that, just to emphasize, right, this pipeline is a very simplified way to
germayne: combine all the elements of the scikit-learns API into a single function to do.fit.transform. But if your use case is complex, and I can tell you guys that for most of the actual use case, it wouldn't be like that.
germayne: then you are basically just writing the code in separate places. You don't have to use it in the pipeline. Does that answer your question, Hitesh?
germayne: Hopefully it does, right? I think that's what you're asking, correct? Yeah. Okay, I'll hand it back again too soon, yeah.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, thank you, Jumin.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… This is the… Code block that.
Soon | NTU: show you how to build a pipeline. Okay, so as much as possible, if you have
Soon | NTU: A dataset, right, with a lot of imputation, scaling, and also one-hour encoding that you need to
Soon | NTU: put in place during the pre-processing, okay? It is always advisable to create a pipeline like this.
Soon | NTU: And because the reason is, if you go to do this manually without using the pipeline, right.
Soon | NTU: You were going to repeat a lot of things.
Soon | NTU: Okay, sometimes, if you're not careful, you may have done
Soon | NTU: Your step in the wrong sequence.
Soon | NTU: Okay? For example, you apply one-haul encoding before you even patch a missing value.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that would be something that is, gonna give you
Soon | NTU: very unexpected result when you go and train the model using this kind of data set, right? And also, using a pipeline
Soon | NTU: Will give you a very consistent, way of… Applying this logic.
Soon | NTU: To your training data, as well as your test data.
Soon | NTU: Where you don't have to do it again.
Soon | NTU: different scaling for your test data, okay? Because when you do scaling, you don't do it on your
Soon | NTU: together with training and the test data together, right? You have to do it separately. Training is training, testing is testing. So, to build a pipeline.
Soon | NTU: So that will mean you are able to control your workflow better.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: And you can also reuse it
Soon | NTU: When you have a deploy, let's say your…
Soon | NTU: Your best model into the production environment.
Soon | NTU: Okay, you deploy your model together with the pipeline for your prediction.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: Let's run this.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this cook block.
Soon | NTU: We'll create your pipeline, for… imputation scaling for the numeric variable. We call it the numerical transformer.
Soon | NTU: And for categorical transformer, it contains the step for imposing missing value and categorical value, as well as applying one-hot encoding.
Soon | NTU: Right? After that, right? So these are only two… there are only two steps in each of these,
Soon | NTU: We call it Transformer.
Soon | NTU: And then… We will combine this transformer into one, Right.
Soon | NTU: Because… This one will take care of both.
Soon | NTU: Numerical and categorical, right?
Soon | NTU: you don't have to say, oh, I have to apply numerical scaling first, and then forward by category correctly. Leave it to SKLearn to do it for you, but in the first place, you have to define the sequence correctly, and then SKLearn will take over and do it
Soon | NTU: The training for you, in this order.
Soon | NTU: Right?
Soon | NTU: So now, logistic regression.
Soon | NTU: It's the model which we are going to train, and then… We will put this
Soon | NTU: Pre-processor and the pipeline together.
Soon | NTU: light is, okay? So… Pipeline variable will store the final workflow, okay, that we will use for our training.
Soon | NTU: It's not modeled. It's not like what we have done before in the…
Soon | NTU: Part 1, right? We immediately call Model Fit, but now it's pipeline dot fit.
Soon | NTU: Which is…
Soon | NTU: Okay. Okay, before that, we will have to go through the process of splitting our data, the 891 Rose.
Soon | NTU: Into 80% training data.
Soon | NTU: Test size is only 20%.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: And this is the train test split function that we need to call, okay? So, do remember the sequence, okay? X, train, X test, Y train, Y test, okay?
Soon | NTU: So, this is always very standard.
Soon | NTU: Statement that you usually need to write, like, when you do your machine learning training, okay?
Soon | NTU: So, pipeline feed will train your model, okay, to identify any pattern in your training data.
Soon | NTU: And then, you will get a prediction based on your test data.
Soon | NTU: Any question up to this point?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yes, I have one question. Just now, I heard you say that you must put the trend variable in order. I don't understand this, statement.
Soon | NTU: wedge.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, here. Pre-processor.
Chieh Cheng Lai: And then you mentioned, because here, get the numerical transformer and category transformer, and then the numerical transformer, you had H,
Chieh Cheng Lai: what's this? Hill batch and fair. So, if I put the fare in front of the edge, will it causing any problem?
Chieh Cheng Lai: And similarly for the category.
Chieh Cheng Lai: if I don't put in this order, I put…
Soon | NTU: Order of the column?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, order, auto column.
Soon | NTU: Order of the column is not important.
Soon | NTU: Because when you do numeric scaling, right, all the scaling
Soon | NTU: Numerical transformer is… it contains two steps, right? Imputation and scaling.
Soon | NTU: Each have its own imputation and scaling done separately from the sibling This is, I think…
Soon | NTU: parent, okay, and… Sibling, spouse, and then…
Soon | NTU: This is a parent, child, and also the fair. So we have 4 different numeric columns.
Soon | NTU: When you do imputation, scaling, all these are done differently.
Soon | NTU: So the scaling you've done for each will not affect your sibling and spouse column, right?
Chieh Cheng Lai: I understand. Then, what do you mean just now? You… because I heard you stress a few times, have to put the…
Chieh Cheng Lai: the, the ver… I mean, somehow, something in…
Soon | NTU: You eat this one?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Not this one before, not… it's on the prep processor.
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, I don't understand on that.
Soon | NTU: Put train variable in order for… Okay, when you do a pipeline, you created a pipeline like this, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: This preprocessor now understands you have a numerical transformation step, as well as categorical transformation step within the pipeline.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: And then… you.
Soon | NTU: In the last pipeline steps, you created preprocessor, Which is this…
Soon | NTU: And then the model, okay? So what this means is, before your model training even started, right?
Soon | NTU: As Caitlin will do the pre-processing for you. Okay, pre-processing, numeric column will be done first, will be done first.
Soon | NTU: age, sibling, spouse, parent, child, and fair, in that order. And then, categorical.
Soon | NTU: Variable will be P class, sex, and embark.
Soon | NTU: Okay? In that order. And then…
Soon | NTU: After that is done, and then your model training will start.
Soon | NTU: So, when you'll start your model training.
Soon | NTU: Cycle, right, the iteration, you would have obtained a very clean cell of data without missing value.
Soon | NTU: And also with the proper, scaling.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, I think I misunderstand, your statement just now. So, you means the order is the… I need to do the preprocessor, to handle the missing data accordingly, like, scaling?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Then, after that, the… followed by the motor and the pipeline that you… you, preprocessor, they put water. So this is all the…
Soon | NTU: Yes, yes. Now, the steps here is important, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, the steps is important.
Soon | NTU: you do not put the model before preprocessor. You can try. Okay, yeah, so it's, it's put… it's run top-down, okay, one after another.
Soon | NTU: Okay? So, you can see… During your training, you don't use model.feed, but you only use a pipeline.fit.
Soon | NTU: Right, so it makes everything very, simple.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Hitesh shah: We are using, random state zero here, because the data is already…
Hitesh shah: There. Why do we need to do a useRandom?
Soon | NTU: Random state?
Hitesh shah: Yeah.
Soon | NTU: A random state is not… It's something to do with the random…
Soon | NTU: Splitting, okay, it is the variable for you to…
Soon | NTU: And should you can reproduce your results.
Soon | NTU: If you say your… let's say your accuracy is 0.9999,
Soon | NTU: So when someone else run it.
Soon | NTU: you are not able to get the 0.999, you know. So, how can I… how can you prove that your result is really 0.99? So, usually, we set a random seed for…
Soon | NTU: Right? Reproducibility.
Hitesh shah: So even if we have a standard set of data and not… we want to have a…
Hitesh shah: I mean, we need to seed the model as well, so we usually use this as most of the time, we seed the model with the standard set.
Soon | NTU: It's a speed for the… Seat for the street.
Hitesh shah: Yeah, okay.
Hitesh shah: Okay, cool.
Soon | NTU: Because your function here, right, When you speak, it's random.
Soon | NTU: Okay, how do you ensure that this time you speed like this, when you run it again, the spitting ratio will be different?
Soon | NTU: Okay, okay. Yep.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so after we run this, we will have the… All the classification metrics, And then we…
Soon | NTU: printed out here. Now, we have a ROC curve, again, on this variable.
Soon | NTU: stored in this variable, so that means we can also plot out our ROC curve later, okay? So… No.
Soon | NTU: For now, if you look at the accuracy, is it very… Hi.
Soon | NTU: Okay, just remember the F1 score, right? Because later, we are going to make use of this 0.74…
Soon | NTU: for Titanic dataset using the logistic regression model.
Soon | NTU: 0074.
Soon | NTU: P.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so next, we're gonna do the same thing.
Soon | NTU: Right?
Soon | NTU: But in this case, we will use a different classifier, call the k-nearest neighbor.
Soon | NTU: Classify your key in info shop, right?
Soon | NTU: So, now, the purpose is, of course, if you have a classification model.
Soon | NTU: sometimes you will ask yourself, you know, which classification model is the best model that I can use for…
Soon | NTU: To, to, to build a classifier for this dataset.
Soon | NTU: Right? Because they all look the same.
Soon | NTU: You could look at a quote, right?
Soon | NTU: Yeah, it looks the same, right?
Soon | NTU: So, let me run this.
Soon | NTU: So, the only difference is you have to choose the right.
Soon | NTU: classifier library from your Sakit-learn.
Soon | NTU: And then, create a model by specifying the name of that.
Soon | NTU: model.
Soon | NTU: The classifier model. Naming.
Soon | NTU: And then the rest are the same.
Soon | NTU: And then, let's look at how…
Soon | NTU: Our K means… our K and N model.
Soon | NTU: perform.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: So, you're playing… 74, same as logistic regression, but the AUC is 0.85 versus 0.87.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, accuracy 0.80,
Soon | NTU: Okay, so some of the metrics are better in logistic regression, some are better for K and N.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so you… In order for you to look at this thing, you know, Bobby, you have to
Soon | NTU: Do a little bit more, testing, right?
Soon | NTU: And also, you can, draw the ROC curve, you know, to compare.
Soon | NTU: how the two curves look like, right? Even though you can see this is 2.85,
Soon | NTU: Logistic regression seem to be performing better in terms of the AUC value.
Soon | NTU: Okay, any questions?
Hitesh shah: So, essentially, what we have built is, based on the parameters we've passed on, we're just checking whether it's a survival rate, whether he survived or not survived. So, there are these.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, yeah.
Hitesh shah: And predict the survival rate.
Soon | NTU: Yes, so whatever we have done is actually to tell the trained model, right, after training, to make the prediction
Soon | NTU: So your prediction, how well we score, right? You will have to use your Y test.
Soon | NTU: Right? The test data that you have set aside.
Soon | NTU: But you don't use X test, you use Y test. Because Y tests contain the 0 and 1,
Soon | NTU: Your model answer in your test data.
Soon | NTU: Right, that 20% that you set aside.
Soon | NTU: Fall.
Soon | NTU: validation purpose.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, based on AUC logistic regression, seem to be performing better than the KNN.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I just realized something.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: so, in here, right, you split the data again for the KNN, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: After the logistic regression.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: If I understand your flow rightly.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Also, here in logistics, you did a split, then at K&N, you also do a split. Then you measure. But how do I know that the data that is used in the logistic and the data used in the K&N is the same for training?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because if it's two different data, then the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: then the number… let me… I value the numbers, right, the metrics, right? Although you've got a number, but then it's based on the sample that you have given, right, the training data that you've given. So, you split two…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Two times, then?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: then the speed may not be the same each time, right? So does it… does it… how does it… would that affect the way we read the metrics?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Even though they're the same measure.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Like, you know, shouldn't we just be split the same, you know, like, you know, like, you split one time, then the same training site is used in K&N, the same site is used in the logistics. Then when you measure the metrics, it's… it's better, right?
Soon | NTU: We only speak once, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: No, they're based on, like, split twice, I'm not sure. I look at the flow that you…
Soon | NTU: Okay, let's.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's like, split two times lah, because you're running, you know, everything in one cell, mah, so I thought you split two times, lah, I'm not sure, I just…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I'm just… These are wise.
Soon | NTU: Let me see.
Soon | NTU: So I split for the DNA regression.
Soon | NTU: Right? Linear regard… Logistic recursion, sorry.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, you speak, then in the can, then you speak again, I think.
Soon | NTU: No.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Jiggy?
Soon | NTU: I did not split for the K&N.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Always, yeah, okay, okay, because I thought it split, though, but it's…
Soon | NTU: Oh, no.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You didn't? Okay, okay, okay, okay. Hang.
Soon | NTU: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Not sure what I got it.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Sorry.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It is clear.
Soon | NTU: Why we use a different scalar?
Soon | NTU: Tengli, we… it's just to illustrate, okay, if there's a need to modify your pipeline.
Soon | NTU: for a different, let's say, model, okay? You… this is the way to do
Soon | NTU: You go and create another new variable.
Soon | NTU: So this will override whatever you have.
Soon | NTU: Created for the logistic regression.
Teng Lee LIM: Yeah, I'm just wondering, like, for K&N, right.
Teng Lee LIM: Is there… why… is there a reason why you use the max scheduler, or…
Soon | NTU: I don't know, there's no reason, you know, that K&N…
Teng Lee LIM: sure.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, no, no, no, yeah, yeah, yeah. Just to show that if there's a need to change your transformer.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Because sometimes you may not only want to train one model, right? You make use of the data, you train many, many models.
Soon | NTU: SVM, Decision 3, because all the classification models all look the same.
Soon | NTU: Feed, predict, and then get your classification metrics.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, so you may want to do it multiple times, and sometimes you may want to reuse or create new transformer for different
Soon | NTU: classifier. Okay, so this is how you would do it.
Soon | NTU: And you may not need to use the same name, you can use a different name.
Soon | NTU: Just to distinguish between transformer you created for the logistic regression and for the KNN.
Teng Lee LIM: Okay, Ken, thank you.
Soon | NTU: You're welcome.
Hitesh shah: So, for the neighbor classifier, we didn't specify any, test data range, right?
Soon | NTU: the test data?
Hitesh shah: Yeah, 20% test and 20% 80% training.
Soon | NTU: No, we did not apply the twin test speed again for K&N.
Soon | NTU: We reused the ratio, just on the way I asked, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, we reuse this for our K&N.
Hitesh shah: Yeah, okay, well, that's fine.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, Jermaine, I have, okay, so I, I… are there any more questions? If not, then I will…
Soon | NTU: hand over to, Jimmy.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I, I, I just wonder… I, I know, you know, earlier when we… last Tuesday, we talked about the… I mean, back to my question, I always find that one easy way to do, one… I find one common…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: easy way, or when I say easy, but one… one tool that can use for many things,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, when it comes to, like, pre-processing, right.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: you were saying earlier that, I know the mean max scale is used just to show us how it's being used here, but… but in reality, we really need to know why we want to use this method or another method, right? I mean, we must be able to explain why we choose that, right? I mean.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, that just makes sure, like, that…
Soon | NTU: Yes, yes, yes. Okay, so you cannot just say, oh, must always use a standard scaler, okay, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You always use normalization, but I think normalization is very nice, but I can't always use normalization all the time, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I don't…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I mean, yeah, to me, no one actually is, like, the best, but I, right, since I had to…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Also, explain why, if I… if I don't use normalization, why do I use… why do I want to keep using normalization if I… there's another one that is better, or like, you know, why the one I choose is better than the other?
germayne: Sorry, sorry to cut you, maybe we discuss that later. We really don't have enough time.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, okay.
germayne: I'm so sorry, everyone, that we really have a lot of content, so it's not like.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I know, I know.
germayne: short, but we really, really, we really, really don't have time. So, so I'm trying to keep up a bit.
germayne: Yeah, okay, I think we can keep the questions separate.
germayne: Yeah.
Soon | NTU: Saturday, on Saturday, we can.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, because it's like, as you go through that, you realize that all this being taught, I learn and come back again, so I just spontaneously ask the question, so… sorry.
germayne: Yeah, no problem, no problem. But yeah, I think let's, let's just bear in mind the time.
Soon | NTU: Adrian has a question, right, Adrian?
germayne: Yeah, yes, Adrian, Adrian. Your hand is up.
germayne: Okay, I think maybe, maybe, maybe we'll, maybe we will come back to that later, yeah.
Soon | NTU: Over to you, Divine.
germayne: Sorry, can you make me the host again?
germayne: Okay, great, thanks.
germayne: Okay, can everyone see my screen?
germayne: Can you guys see my screen? Okay. Okay, so I, I think before I… before I… before… oh, sorry.
germayne: before I start, right, I think just one… one commentary… one commentary. Again, don't… don't take it that I'm discouraging guys from asking questions. I think you guys, you know, you guys can ask any question. But one thing I noticed, right, is that, actually now is actually… you guys are already at Module 3.
germayne: So, what this means, right, is that by right, you guys should be very familiar with
germayne: going into the documentation. So if you just go and Google SKLearn, right, for any of the functions, you should be able to see a very good documentation, and
germayne: what I want to encourage the class is that when you ask questions, don't ask, like… like, I think you guys can ask, but
germayne: what I'm just trying to give feedback to you guys, right, is that some questions I feel is that, I'm a bit worried that if you guys finish the class, and then the takeaway is that you're not independent enough to read the documentation, right, then I'm a bit concerned, because
germayne: the goal here, right, shouldn't be that you walk out with this knowing how to use sklearn Library. The library is really, really not important.
germayne: the… some of the… some of the things, right, is… I think eventually, if you try it out, you will just know how it works, based on the way the API works. And one example, I think, for the question on pipeline, right, is that pipeline is so specific to SKLearn, it's like, it is just a way that SKLearn designed to… to use the thing.
germayne: we, you know, if you guys really want me to teach you guys, yeah, I can teach you guys that, but I don't think it's meaningful, because
germayne: When you graduate out of the class.
germayne: you are… you will want to be like, oh, okay, actually, I have very good fundamental, how can I use a different library? Then you will start from scratch again. Okay, the library will not explain how to use, you need to go into the documentation again. You need to go and see, like, oh, okay, this library asked me to use this method to fit the model. Okay, so therefore I'm going to do this.
germayne: So, my takeaway for you guys is that
germayne: If at this point, right, you're not independent enough to be able to read an API doc to understand, then you guys need to start doing that now, because I think the takeaway is for you guys to be independent.
germayne: You guys understand where I'm coming from, right? Because I don't want you guys to, like, oh, I know how to use specific library taught in the class, but the world is… there's so many libraries, people are always writing new stuff. If you are into things like LLM,
germayne: Oh gosh, like, new libraries are up almost every week, every month.
germayne: And if you cannot, like.
germayne: relearn, right, new libraries, then you won't be able to pick up again. So I think that's the feedback for some of you guys, okay? But still, if let's say you read the document and you don't understand, right, really happy to help. Let's say you look at this, oh man, hey Jermaine, or soon, I'm still, like, quite confused.
germayne: I'm very, very sure we'll be happy to help. Okay, but anyways, enough of me talking. Okay, so I think I'll tell you guys what will happen for these next two hours.
germayne: very unlikely we cannot finish, all the content for 3.4 as well, so we will definitely have to spill over to Saturday, right?
germayne: So, for remaining 3.3, right, what I will do is I'll spend the next half an hour
germayne: About half an hour, to go through the regression metrics.
germayne: And I'll talk a bit about the bias-variance trade-off.
germayne: And for the exercise, right, I think for the sake of continuity and for the class to be a bit smoother.
germayne: I will… we won't… we won't do the… we won't do the… the exercise again. The exercise later on, I think we can… we can push some of these exercises back to… back to Saturday, if needed, right? Then I will try to go over to 3.4. But can I ask anybody at this point in time need to go for toilet break? Maybe some of you guys need to go.
germayne: You guys need to go for bio break. We do a 5 minutes, okay?
germayne: Yeah, let's have a 5-minute video break. Okay. Then we'll come back, yeah. Let's come back at 8.18. Yeah.
germayne: By the way, right, for those of you who are not going on break, I also added the 3.4 nodes into the chat drive already.
germayne: So you guys also can download when we reach there, yeah.
germayne: Okay, so… so… I think while some of you are on the break, this is on… this… this notes is actually on 3.3.
germayne: I think this is 3.3…
germayne: Yeah, so I think the… the last part we stopped at was the… the ROC-AUC… sorry, AUC-ROC curve.
germayne: Okay, so we'll start on the regression metric, then we will finish off on the… on the bias-variance trade-off.
germayne: Yeah, I don't think the… the… I don't think the code is really very important, to be honest.
germayne: I feel like that, that those you guys can do, but we will, we will cover, probably cover that on Saturday.
germayne: Yeah, so I think what… what… what soon actually went through you guys to some extent is important, because
germayne: when you guys do the Kaggle later on, you guys need to use the library, right? So I think that part is relevant.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: But again, right, what I want to re-emphasize again, right, many times, is that
germayne: the… you have the flexibility to do whatever… to really code the way you want. You don't have to be restricted to these libraries. Yeah.
germayne: Okay, but fun fact, I hardly ever use pipelines.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: It's not… you can write your own… you can write each of the modules separately, you don't have to do the pipelines, yeah. It's not needed, but if you really want the whole ecosystem of scikit-learn, then, of course, using their API, using the pipelines has its merit.
germayne: Right, yeah.
germayne: Okay, okay, so I will start so, for those of you who were on break, the… I added the 3.4 PDF in the chat folder as well, so later, if you guys want the notes, the notes will be inside.
germayne: Okay, so I'm going to… I'm going to get started on the regression metric. So, on Tuesday, we talked about the classification metrics, right? We talk about everything. You guys just now saw the code examples already.
germayne: So today we are going to talk about regression. So again, right, the term regression here refers to the problem formulation. So you're doing a regression problem, not a regression model, okay, just to emphasize.
germayne: So, regression metrics basically means that your prediction, your Y and your Y hat.
germayne: We are always talking about continuous value.
germayne: Continuous variable… continuous value.
germayne: Right? So we need, again, right, the whole point of a metric is, once you have some kind of model, how can I actually evaluate and assess whether if the model is trained correctly?
germayne: We are not talking about validation, we are going to talk about validation later, right? Validation means how do you actually prepare the dataset to validate? But now we are talking about measuring, right? Metrics just basically means from a measuring perspective.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: So regression metrics are actually all these very common metrics. Some of it, you guys probably have seen it, some of it, probably you guys have not seen it, right? We talk a bit about, we talk a bit about R-square.
germayne: We talk about art, oh, wait, huh?
germayne: We talk about… we talk about R-square, and adjusted R-square, I also sort of mentioned to you guys, right? So, R-square, you guys can actually see that
germayne: R-square, in the formula, right, is actually highly correlated to mean square error, because it measures the variance. So essentially, if you have a model that improves mean square error, R-square will definitely be improved as well, from a formulation perspective, right? So.
germayne: Here, I think R-square, sort of, like, we went through already, so I don't want to spend so much time on it, but SKLearn also allows you to use R-square to measure, right? So, in this case, you see that there's 5 metrics. The question here is that.
germayne: probably you guys would have would be similar to the classification, where each metric, again, has a kind of idea of what you want to measure, and each of them are actually measuring different things, right? So what this means is that
germayne: The ideal workflow is that you need to be very clear what is it that you want to measure in your model, rather than to measure all five of them.
germayne: Some of them is monotonic. Monotonic means that if one is better, the other will also be better. Very good example here is R-square.
germayne: and MSE, right?
germayne: If MSE is improved, R-squared will definitely improve, okay? Just look at the formula and you'll understand, okay? The idea here is… but then, apart from these two.
germayne: Your… your… okay, actually, this… this… actually, everything is… this is… okay, so number 1 is actually correlated with number 2 is actually correlated with number 3.
germayne: Okay, number 4, we don't really use it unless it's for linear regression. This is mostly for linear regression.
germayne: Right? And I explained it on Saturday already. But, in terms of machine learning.
germayne: one, one, the first, second, and third, right, that I illustrated here, they're actually correlated.
germayne: Right? I'm going to explain a bit from my intuition, we are going to go through each of it, okay? One side note, actually, we have seen mean square error. Anybody knows where did we see mean square error? So, mean square error, right, the formula is just summation, for each of your Y.
germayne: So basically, this is a formula, which means it's a square error, right? For each of my predictions, I take the difference with the actual value, and I square it.
germayne: Anybody has a guess where do we see this formula? We've actually seen it.
germayne: We went through this.
Zac Ang: Standard error.
germayne: No, not standard error.
germayne: I gave a hint. Very… We talk about these in linear regression.
Zac Ang: residuals.
germayne: Exactly, the square, there's a square residual, right? SSR, right? I think… I believe Shuming mentioned.
germayne: And if you remember, if you remember, we sort of talk about SSR as the sum of squared error. Basically, this is a squared error. This is… you can see from the formula, right? This is error.
germayne: It's a difference between what I predicted with the actual value and I square it.
germayne: Right? So essentially, right, you can start to see here that OLS
germayne: in its closed form solution, actually minimizes square error. So what does it mean? It means that indirectly, it's actually minimizing mean square error, okay? So actually, we have seen that.
germayne: Okay, so I'm going to talk about the first error, okay? Mean absolute error. So if you look at the formula.
germayne: Mean absolute error, basically, there's an absolute sign here, and we are basically taking the target value, the actual prediction, minus your predicted value, and we take an absolute value.
germayne: So, you notice that this absolute value will basically nullify the direction of your prediction, whether you're underestimating or overestimating, correct? Because we take an absolute value. And what we do is we take an average.
germayne: So, why is it that people choose to use MEE? Sometimes it's because MEE, obviously, is very easy to interpret.
germayne: Agreed? From a business standpoint, ME is very easy to interpret, right? I'm just taking a difference between my prediction. I take the absolute value, and I take the average. So it's the average…
germayne: Or rather, the mean absolute error. Basically, on average, how far I'm wrong.
germayne: Okay, so one reason why you might want to choose this is because it's very easy to interpret, right? However, the metric, as you can see, mean absolute error, is actually quite robust to outliers.
germayne: Okay, and in order to maximize mean absolute error, usually if you predict the median, mean absolute error would love it.
germayne: Right? Because min absolute error, you can see later on when we start to contrast with mean square error, you can see that mean absolute error is more robust to outliers as compared to mean square error.
germayne: Right? So you can see this is one example of a metric.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: This is the one that we talk about. Essentially, rather than take an absolute value, now you're just basically squaring the error.
germayne: And in your head, right, you'll be thinking, why… why do I want to square the error, right? So, if you look at… if you look at an error profile, right, mean square error actually looks like that. It's actually a curved shape.
germayne: So what this means is that, as the error starts to get larger, so the…
germayne: the x-axis is your Y minus y hat square, right? Has the arrow starts to get larger.
germayne: Oh, sorry, actually…
germayne: Yeah, so the x-axis is actually your Y minus Y hat, your y-axis is your squared error, and you can see that the intuition here is that when you try to square the error, errors that are very large.
germayne: Will be very huge.
germayne: Okay, so what this means is that the larger… the larger your error is, the larger the error, the larger it gets amplified, right? A very, very good example is if your difference is 2,
germayne: If your difference between your predictor is 2,
germayne: Your error is actually going to be a 4.
germayne: But if, let's say, it's a 10,
germayne: Right? Just basically from 2 to 10.
germayne: 10 becomes 100.
germayne: So you can start to see, right, that the error basically starts to increase exponentially. You guys can see that, right, from an intuition standpoint. So what this means is that if you were to choose to use MSE,
germayne: It is going to be very sensitive to outliers.
germayne: Right? What this means is that if your model were to make any bad prediction.
germayne: The model will be forced to emphasize… will be forced to focus on that, because
germayne: The cost of me making a very big mistake is going to be huge.
germayne: So I'm rather… if I can focus on correcting my misprediction for a very huge error.
germayne: I'm going to… I'm going to improve the model a lot, as compared to me predicting too. So, if you were to use this, right, basically what… what is happening is that you're going to choose a model that is going to be good at not making very big mistakes, as compared to your mean absolute error.
germayne: Because mean absolute error doesn't care. Mean absolute error is essentially just the difference between the arrows, right? It's just a minus, and then you just take absolute value. But mean square error, because when you're squaring it.
germayne: The resulting error profile will be very big.
germayne: Okay, so why would you want to choose this? You want to choose this if, let's say, your focus is to ensure that you don't make any big mistakes. You want to ensure that your model doesn't have cases where, you know, maybe, maybe, maybe, let's say if I have, 10 samples, again, this is a very hypothetical example.
germayne: And I have one, one, one sample, or maybe let's say I have two samples here.
germayne: Right.
germayne: I want to choose MSC if I ensure that all 12 samples don't have huge Arrow jump.
germayne: you can have perfect prediction for 10 samples, but the moment you have 2 samples that have very huge error, your overall MSC is going to be very bad, and you'll want to capture that as a metric.
germayne: So… That is the point of using mean square error.
germayne: Okay? Now, to relate this back to your OILS, if you remember your linear regression.
germayne: Your OLS, because OLS, as we know from a theory standpoint, it is always maximizing your sum of square residual. Your sum of square residual, in terms of formula, is actually the same as your MSE.
germayne: So what does this mean?
germayne: This means that your linear regression model is actually very sensitive to outliers.
germayne: And it makes sense, right? If you think about it from a curve.
germayne: If this is my dot, Right?
germayne: And I have a… I… I have a… I have a… I have a… I have an outlier all the way at the end.
germayne: Do you think the linear regression model will ignore the outlier? The linear regression model will not, right? Because it will try to fit
germayne: It will try to fit everybody, if you remember.
germayne: Why is it that I'm not able to… So, yeah?
germayne: So, in your linear regressions case, right, if let's say, you have an outlier point, your line will always try to fit that average.
germayne: And that is the whole point of mean square error, because I cannot afford to make any mistakes for a very big error. I can't afford to ignore someone, right? Especially if there's an outlier.
germayne: So what this means is that your OLS, right, your linear regression, is actually very sensitive to outliers, because any outliers will cause a huge error, and any huge error when measured by a mean square error is going to be amplified, because of the square.
germayne: Okay, so hopefully you guys get the… get the… the intuition from mean square error, as opposed to mean absolute error. So mean absolute error tend to ignore outliers.
germayne: Right? Because it's just caring about absolute differences.
germayne: Okay? So every mistake that you make is just going to be that mistake proportional to the mistake that you make. I'm not going to penalize it much more as compared to
germayne: your other values. So basically, the error is just linear, right? But here, your error is
germayne: You can think of it like exponential, because it's square.
germayne: Okay? But anybody wants to make a guess.
germayne: What's the drawback of mean square error?
germayne: Anybody knows.
germayne: Let's say today, if we were to do the housing price prediction.
germayne: And we measure using mean square error, what do you think will be, what do you think… what do you think will be one drawback of using this?
germayne: From a business intuition.
germayne: Anybody knows.
germayne: No one?
germayne: No one knows?
germayne: Nobody wants to give a try.
Kim Meng Phoa: skill dependent.
germayne: Fantastic.
germayne: So the problem here is the scale will be very weird, right?
germayne: If your prediction is your HDB ratio price, you do mean square error.
germayne: I'm taking the difference between my prediction for the resale prices.
germayne: minus the actual price, and I'm squaring it. So basically, you're going to get something like, you're gonna get a very big…
germayne: Let's say some kind of very big number.
germayne: And how are you going to interpret it?
germayne: So the number is meaningless to people, right? You just know that the smaller, the better.
germayne: Correct? So, very hard to report to stakeholders, but good for measuring outliers, good for measuring variance in mistakes. When I say variance, again, it's this example where you can be perfect for two, but the moment you make very big mistake for 2, the variance of your prediction error is very big, you're going to have very bad mean square error.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Now…
germayne: To amplify the problem of the metric not being measurable, you basically just add a square root. So that's why we have the root mean square error, okay? So mathematically, can I ask you guys, now that if you look at the formula, do you think the root mean square error and mean square error is monotonic?
germayne: Monotonic, again, means that if I improve mean square error, does it mean that I improve, sorry, if I improve root mean square error, does it mean that I improve mean square error?
germayne: I do, right? Because I'm only scaling it by a square root.
germayne: So any model that improves mean root mean square error would improve mean square error.
germayne: Okay, but the benefit now is that the output of the error is now in the same unit, because
germayne: We are taking the difference, we apply a square to penalize the huge error, but we are doing a square root back to transform it back to the unit. So again, in the context of the housing price in Kaggle.
germayne: When we do root mean square error, it will be the error in dollar value.
germayne: Okay, so you can see it's easier to interpret. But again, again, the property of penalizing
germayne: Big mistakes still exist.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so the key takeaway, I would say, is this. There are some cases that people use R-square, okay? I have experienced this before. R-square, right, very easy to interpret also, because it's just between 0 and 1.
germayne: It's just between 0 and 1.
germayne: And people usually know that if R-squared is higher, it's actually better.
germayne: But one big difference here, when we are discussing this metric, right, from a machine learning perspective, which I will emphasize later in the validation thing that I'll talk about, is that this R-square and adjusted R-square, right, that we saw in linear regression, if you guys remember on Saturday, I showed you guys the stats summary, right? Remember?
germayne: The stat summary talks about the fitted error. So what it means is that in your training data, this is the training data that you use to train your prediction, right?
germayne: To train your linear regression, if you remember your linear regression model.
germayne: In linear regression, we don't care about prediction, we care about inference. So there's no concept of, like, oh, you know, taking something to validate. You're only… you have a… you have a bunch of,
germayne: You have a bunch of… Wait.
germayne: We have a bunch of data.
germayne: And you're using the same data.
germayne: same value, and you have the same prediction, right? And what you're basically doing is you're just… you just want to assess how good the fit is for the linear regression.
germayne: In this case, what you are seeing here, R-square, is the measurement of R-square on your whole data, which I'll talk about it later. And from a formulation perspective, it's actually
germayne: Co-related to your… sorry, it's actually…
germayne: monotonic to your mean squared error, because the top formula for R-squared, basically, is 1 minus your squared error, right? Basically, your squared error, divided by variance.
germayne: With respect to me.
germayne: So, the example here is that we are validating it on something else, which we'll talk about it later. But the summary here, right, the takeaway is for…
germayne: For MAE, for MSE, and for RMSE, the lower, the better, because we are always talking about error. In a perfect world, if your model can predict every value with 100% accuracy, the error will be zero, if you look at the formula. So the lower, the better.
germayne: Okay? MEE, from a model perspective, right, MEE,
germayne: If you were to use MAE, right, the interpretation is that it is less sensitive to huge errors, because the error profile basically just looks like that.
germayne: So basically, every increment in error is just increased linearly.
germayne: Right? So it's less susceptible to huge error. So the model will not… if, let's say, you're using MAE as an evaluation metric, you're going to choose a model that is less sensitive to making extreme mistakes. Which means, right, if your model is making some kind of huge error, you might not be able to detect it.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Mean square arrow, as I mentioned.
germayne: Because the error profile is squared, right? So the graph again looks like that. Which means an error at the extreme area is going to be much higher as compared to the error made at the bottom.
germayne: exponentially, because of the square, right? You can see, right, the curve, actually, it goes upwards. So you can see how the error starts to increase very, very quickly at extreme ends, which makes it good for penalizing very huge error.
germayne: Okay? Actually, the differentiability, we'll talk about it later, is not defined at zero, but it can be… it can be differentiated everywhere except zero. Okay? But not important today. We'll talk about it at gradient descent, mathematically. Okay? Mean square error is exactly the same as your mean square error, okay?
germayne: So actually, that… that is the… that… and of course, there are still many, many, many metrics, but these are the common ones that people will always use to evaluate. And again, for Kaggle, we'll be using root-min-square error.
germayne: Okay, I'll pause here first. Anybody has any questions so far?
germayne: Okay, no questions, huh?
germayne: Can I, can I continue?
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so before we move on to the last part, right, I just want to emphasize one last thing.
germayne: When you train a model, right, when you train a model, so far.
germayne: So far, what we have always been talking about is to check some kind of metric on it.
germayne: But actually, right, internally, the model, from a mathematical standpoint, the model is always optimizing something, right? When we say train a model, right, conceptually, it's actually an optimization process. It's actually trying to minimize something.
germayne: So essentially, right, from a model perspective, it needs to have some kind of objective function, or loss function, in order to perform its optimization process.
germayne: Right? So what this actually means is that, from an ML perspective.
germayne: Your offline metric, which is the one that I've been talking about, is actually very related to your loss.
germayne: Okay, I want to emphasize again, the loss is basically your loss function.
germayne: Which means, from a mathematical perspective.
germayne: the machine learning algorithm, it needs to know what is the objective for me to train, right? And if you think about it, right, like, in martial arts film, right, if you're training for something, you need to have a goal.
germayne: Right?
germayne: From a human perspective, I have told you guys that there's actually 3… 3 metrics in reality.
germayne: You have your online, which is usually what the business people looked at. You have your offline, which is what we have been discussing, and actually now, suddenly, Jamin is talking about a loss function. Well, the good news is that the loss function has some kind of relationship with your offline metric.
germayne: But I want you guys to… I want you guys… I want to ask you guys a question from your intuition standpoint. You don't have the answer, because I haven't told you guys yet. But from an intuition standpoint, right, do you guys think that every possible offline metric
germayne: It's possible to be used in the laws?
germayne: Anybody wants to make a guess.
germayne: So we talked a bit about all of these metrics. Above, we have all the precision, recall, everything, right?
germayne: The question here is, do you think every metric from the offline bucket, right.
germayne: Is optimisable in the loss function perspective.
germayne: So, again, right, for those of you that don't catch my question, online metric is what business people look at, offline metric is what you guys look at, but then from a machine learning standpoint, the machine algorithm model, right, the math model, right, it needs to also look at something.
germayne: Correct. So, the question here is, do you think that all the metrics that we covered in… okay, maybe instead of talking about the offline one first, right? How about I guide you guys to the answer?
germayne: Do you guys think it's possible that online metric is actually measurable by the machine learning model?
germayne: Some say yes, some say no.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I didn't know.
germayne: Yeah, so you're right, so it's not measurable… the machine learning model cannot directly look at your business metric.
germayne: Right? What about? Okay, now with that intuition.
germayne: try to, try to, try to make a guess. Is every possible offline metric measurable as a loss function by the machine learning model?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Mathematically, it's possible.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I don't see why it's not, right? I mean, it's like, unless… unless the graph is… the function is a very weird function, that it doesn't really…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You know, get down to a… to a loss, or there might be multiple… like, some… some ground has very funny shape,
germayne: Exactly, okay. I think the intuition is good, yeah. So I should, yeah, correct.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Maybe, maybe it got a different, different, different low value, you know, compared to maybe…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I read… that's what I read about the… the… I mean, I'm coming home,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: graph point of view, lah, math graph point of view, then, yeah, then it's pos… no, you'll try to get back to minimum, but it may not be actually the… I mean, the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the minimum that we, you know, that is in the function depends on how the thing is, right? So…
germayne: Okay, so I… I will tell you guys that… We will get to the minimum now. I'll tell you…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Some kind of minimal. Some kind of minimum. Math is correct, in that sense, lah, yeah.
germayne: So, okay, I think good, good, good, good, good try. I think, Noelia, good try. But the sad reality is that if the machine learning model can always optimize your offline metric, then it will be perfect.
germayne: Correct? Which means that whatever you want to measure, the machine learning model can always minimize it.
germayne: But unfortunately, that is not the case.
germayne: Right? And depending on the optimization process, there are some properties that the algorithm actually… sorry, there are some properties where the optimization process, right, actually requires the function to have.
germayne: Right? Very, very simple example that you will see later on is that it requires the function to be differentiable.
germayne: Right? But not everything is… not everything, as you can see, can be differentiated.
germayne: Okay, not everything can be differentiated. So, the unfortunate reality is that not everything can be a loss function from your offline metric, which will explain, right, in reality, why, for example, in your classification.
germayne: if you are… if, let's say, you are very interested in AUC ROC,
germayne: or ROC AUC, right? Area under the ROC curve.
germayne: Right? This is not differentiable.
germayne: So what this means is that no algorithm can differentiate this metric directly.
germayne: And the implication of this means that there's always going to be some
germayne: gap between what you are trying to measure versus what the model can minimize, okay? Now, to put… to put this… to put this into perspective, what this means is that
germayne: you might not directly improve the metric that you are interested in, for example, if you are interested in AUC, ROC, right?
germayne: you might not directly improve this. So you're using some other function, to find…
germayne: your best possible ROC AUC that you can find. And what makes matters worse is that your business metric is also not directly optimisable.
germayne: What this means is that a model with 0.98
germayne: AUCROC might not be the metric that you're interested in.
germayne: Right? Which makes sense. A good model that is able to do classification might not be the best model to increase your business.
germayne: Right? So let's say from your business metric standpoint, you want something where most people will want to click. Let's say your metric is click-through rate.
germayne: CTR.
germayne: Right? CTR has a metric, it's not your ROC AUC.
germayne: Okay, so that's why this is very challenging, and you will start to see this in Kaggle. Bye right.
germayne: But I gave you guys a very easy, easy, easy, easier metric, right? We have a metric that we can directly optimize, because we know that
germayne: We know that, empirically.
germayne: sorry, not empirically. We know that from a closed-form solution, right, OLS can already minimize mean square error, so it must be then able to minimize RMSE, right? Linear regression does it.
germayne: It finds, given your parameters, the best mean square error. By the way, right.
germayne: when I say the best, it doesn't mean that globally the best. If you put in nonsense in your model, the best that you can find based on what you have given, right, is the best based on your data set. It's not the universal best.
germayne: Make sense, huh?
germayne: So if today you go into Kaggle in your groups, Group 1, for example, train a model.
germayne: Hey, then you're like, Jermaine says that OLS gives you the best, but good OLS gives the best based on whatever input that you give. It optimizes the best based on what you give, but doesn't mean that yours is the best in the whole world. Because otherwise, then, good 1, good 2, good 3, good 4, good 5 will just arrive at the same answer, right?
germayne: Correct?
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so I think… I think this is the last part. I'm just going to go very, very quickly through this, right? This is important from a theoretical standpoint, about bias-variance trade-off in machine learning.
germayne: Okay? So I'll just go through what the slide says, and then I'll give you guys a bit of intuition. Okay? The idea is that when you train machine learning model, there's something called the bias-variance trade-off.
germayne: Which means, right.
germayne: When you start to have a model that is very good at high… that has high variance, your bias will start to go down. If you have a model that has high bias, your variance will start to go down. And this is going to be a very common theme in machine learning.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: So one way to think about buyers, right, a very hand-wavy way to talk about buyers, right, is that buyers, right, is essentially, you can think of it as the easiest way to think of buyers is essentially just underfit.
germayne: Okay, what does underfeit mean?
germayne: If you… if you were to look at the chart on the right-hand side, I'm going to go a bit bigger.
germayne: what do you guys think is the true… and again, let's assume that this is the population data. Imagine this is the true population data. Of course, you do not have access to this, hypothetically.
germayne: What do you… which… which… which, which color, which line, right, best capture the relationship of the dataset?
germayne: Is it the blue, or is it the red?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Great one.
germayne: The red one, right?
germayne: But now, if you look at the linear regression.
germayne: You notice that linear regression cannot have that curve, because based on definition, it must be linear, right? The definition of a linear regression model is that it must be linear. So what this means is that
germayne: As best as possible, right? No matter how smart you are, no matter how many data sets that you put.
germayne: the linear regression has its own constraint, because of the assumptions that data sets is linear in relationship. But in this example, you can see that X and Y is obviously nonlinear.
germayne: So what happens is that when you fit a model like that, It's basically called underfitting, because
germayne: One way to think about it is.
germayne: High bias means it's underfitting, and the intuition here is that there's a lot of assumptions in the model, which makes it very constrained, right?
germayne: Now, let me give you another example. If, let's say, right, this is the curve, if I have a model that fits perfectly every single corner.
germayne: Right, my model, very complex.
germayne: Right? I feed every single dot perfectly.
germayne: In this case, right, the idea here is the model is very flexible, right? Very flexible to move around the area.
germayne: Right? It has a lot of flexibility. But if you think about the linear regression model, the linear regression model is actually very rigid.
germayne: And why is it rigid? Because he has a lot of assumptions about the data, about the model.
germayne: And therefore, in this case, it's actually underfitting.
germayne: You're not actually able to fit the correct
germayne: underlying function to actually predict the data. So this is actually called high bias.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Now, on the other hand, What is high variance?
germayne: If you look at this dataset again.
germayne: If I… if I were to have another line that fits perfectly, let me give an illustration. I'm going to fit perfectly every single point.
germayne: This is essentially a definition of overfitting.
germayne: So high buyers means underfitting, high variance means overfitting.
germayne: Which means, right, even though there's some nonsense data, your model is also trying to capture it. So now your model is too flexible, right? The previous case was the model not very flexible, now your model too flexible. It's capturing a lot of noise. So what this means is that the moment, right.
germayne: your model overfeeds, it means that if I were to take a different sample of data and train the model again, I'm going to get a different outcome. That's why it's called high variance.
germayne: Right? If I change the data again, I resample the data again. Let's say today, right, I have a model.
germayne: X, I train F of X,
germayne: Right? I have a model that gives a prediction.
germayne: Tomorrow, if I resample a data, I have a new subset of data. I try F of X.
germayne: And you get a completely different output.
germayne: all your Y2 and all your Y1 is going to be very different. That's why it's called high variance. Because, right, your model is so fitted to your training data that it is as good as memorizing. I think, I believe that was a term that Shumin used, right? It's like memorizing.
germayne: It's like, if you go for exam, you are so good that
germayne: If the same exact questions were to come out, you can score 100%, but the moment I give you a different question, similar concept, you can't score it.
germayne: So, essentially, the idea is you are so good at your training data, but you learn nothing.
germayne: Right? You're basically overfitting.
germayne: Okay, so the central idea here, right, the takeaway, is that biased.
germayne: and variants.
germayne: They are basically like a… like a… like a different trade-off, and you're always trying to balance in between.
germayne: Right? You don't want a model that is underfitting, neither do you want… and here is underfit.
germayne: And here is Overfeed.
germayne: You don't want a model that is
germayne: only useful for your own training data, because that defeats the point, right? You want to model something that is able to capture the relationship.
germayne: But at the same time, you don't want to underfeed that.
germayne: The model is just only giving the same value for certain output, doesn't learn anything.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So basically, this is the trade-off.
germayne: Okay, and you can look at the graph, right? Basically, what it's trying to say is this is the error.
germayne: And this is the model complexity. Model complexity just basically means that how complex your model is, right?
germayne: I consider an example where your model is very simple. This is a very simple model.
germayne: Versus?
germayne: Let's say your model becomes something like that.
germayne: Right? This model is going to be more complex than this model, right? So essentially, the idea here is that… and of course, as you start to introduce more and more advanced algorithms, the model becomes more and more complex.
germayne: Right? We no longer need to adhere to the linear relationship criteria, right?
germayne: And you can start to see here that as you start to train your model, as you start to make the model more complex, your bias is naturally going to decrease, because you're going to make less assumptions about the data, you're going to be more flexible. But at the trade-off, your variance is going to start to increase.
germayne: Okay? And it's very hard to get this balance. In reality, you won't have access to this curve.
germayne: So you have to assess whether, if your model is able to generalize or not.
germayne: Okay, so conceptually, that's the whole idea of bias-variance trade-off. Okay? Usually, if you were to go happen to… if any of you happen to go to data science interview, they like to ask this question. This is like a machine learning 101 question. They always ask this, what is… what is bias-variance trade-off? Everybody always asks this.
germayne: Okay, I mean, I can't say, like, the whole world, but it's a very common question.
germayne: Okay, so anyway, the last illustration, right, this is also a very common truck that they give.
germayne: So imagine, right, if your goal is to hit the bull's eye, right? Obviously, if in a perfect world.
germayne: If you were to shoot an arrow, low bias, low variance just means that you're always going to hit the bull's eye.
germayne: low buyers, high variance means that you're going to be very widely spread. You can see, you shoot the arrow, you're going to, like… you're shooting around the bull's eye, but you can see the variance very huge.
germayne: Right? Model really not accurate.
germayne: High buyers, low variance, what does it mean?
germayne: Means that, right, you have some assumption.
germayne: Right? You're going to predict very similar values, but off the target.
germayne: Right?
germayne: If you're… obviously, this is the worst lah. This one you might have, so just don't use any model.
germayne: Okay? So basically, you can see the illustration here.
germayne: Of the concept of
germayne: when you've underfit your model all the way to overfit. We're going to talk about it later in details, because
germayne: So far, we are only talking about training models at face value, but as a user.
germayne: There's a lot of inputs from you that's required.
germayne: Okay? So the last point to just… to talk… Last point to cover, cross-validation, we'll talk about it later. Basically, cross-validation means that, how are you going to design a way to validate that your model is actually performing well? Right, we'll talk about that later.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: This is a very famous thing, right? If you were to take… or anybody knows who Andrew Wang is? Anybody knows Andrew Wang from Stanford?
germayne: father of deep learning, father of machine learning. Nobody knows.
Edwin Yap: Tell me about those.
germayne: Some people don't know. Some people know. Okay, so some people don't know.
Edwin Yap: blessed.
germayne: Exactly. So, Andrew famously said, right, if you want to reduce variance, you just have more training data.
germayne: Right? And the idea here is that, because if you don't want to overfit, you just provide more relevant examples for the model, right? Correct? If you can have very good, diverse coverage of training data, you're exposing the models to more and more training data. That's a good thing, right? Think of it as your language model.
germayne: Right? If you remember, one, two years ago, GPT is basically nonsense, right? GPT-3 is like shit. 3.5. Very, very bad. But as you start to have more methodology to give diverse, examples for the model to get exposed, basically, you can start to train the performance to be better, right?
germayne: Okay, so feature selection. Obviously, this is something that, you guys would… this will probably be the biggest challenge for you guys in Kaggle, because I gave you guys 77 dataset, 77 features. Your goal is to determine how to engineer and extract value out of these 77. You can create more, you can create all the way up to 200.
germayne: Right? But you're going to face a challenge of feature selection.
germayne: Regularization, we'll talk about… we're going to talk about it later. Basically, the idea is, how do you actually
germayne: Enforce certain penalty to your model training to prevent the model from overtraining too much, overfitting too much.
germayne: And of course, there's also ensemble method, which is also quite popular from… from Kaggle, right? Basically, idea of ensembling, right, from a hand-weavy perspective is, if today I were to ask Josiah to give me an answer, versus if I were to ask Josiah, Zach, Teng Li, Qin Meng, I ask all of you guys, and all of you guys tell me the same answer.
germayne: Asking… asking an answer from 5 different people is going to be better than asking the answer from 1.
germayne: Makes sense, right? If 5 people tell me the same answer.
germayne: is going to be stronger than one person giving me the answer. So the idea here of ensemble is that if you can combine prediction from multiple different models, and because each of these models have its own biases and variances, you can actually reduce variance.
germayne: Right? So that's actually the intuition, and we'll be talking about them probably on Saturday. I don't think we'll be talking about ensemble methods today.
germayne: Okay, can I go on? All good.
germayne: Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I, I got a… Christian? Yes.
germayne: Yes.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You're not the answer now, I'm just… but as you were going through the metrics, I realized that
Low Keng Teck, Noel: My approach would always be, like, find a model, then… you use the model, then you check whether the model is good to use the metrics.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But after you teach, it seems like I should try to find out what the metric is before I find the model.
germayne: Exactly, exactly, you should, because if you realize that every metric is…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Nice.
germayne: If you realize that every metric has its pros and cons, right?
germayne: If you don't really know what you… what's the main objective that you want from a model, then printing all the metrics doesn't really help, right?
germayne: Right? Your precision recall, everything is all different.
germayne: So you need to know… I feel like you need to know what metric you want first, and that's actually a very important skill set.
germayne: Okay, so I'm going to go to 3.4, right, today. We won't be able to cover everything, right? So I probably won't rush, but what we will probably go through today is at least we'll finish number 1 and number two, okay? If we've got time, we can do number 3, but we'll leave the last one to Saturday.
germayne: Okay? So I think you guys have been asking a lot of questions on the validation, so not that I don't want to share, but part of the curriculum is to share now, right? 3.4. So we'll talk a bit about validation, and I'll spend some time on this, because this is super, super important.
germayne: Okay, but before we talk about the rest, we'll talk a bit about regularization first, okay?
germayne: Okay, so basically, right, if you remember just now, we talked about the high variance, right? Essentially, overfeed, right? Just to remind again, overfeed in the interview, right? People say, oh, what is buyer's variance trade-off? Basically, it's just talking about the overfitting, underfitting, right?
germayne: So again, right, regularization is a technique, right, usually aimed to reduce your high variance. Basically, I want to prevent my model from… if you look at the… if you look at the graph here.
germayne: This model, right, the red color line, is really, really overfitting like crazy. You can see, right, the model is so complex, right, versus a model that is, like, on the right-hand side, where the curve is very smooth, very natural, right? Very, very natural curve.
germayne: Right? So the idea is that, similarly.
germayne: Because the machine learning model, right, they are not sentient, they are really just a math model, right? The algo basically just needs some ingredients from you. It needs your X, it needs your Y, and it needs a loss function.
germayne: Basically, the loss function, right? As you guys learned, one example is your mean square arrow.
germayne: So from an optimization standpoint, it will want to minimize, let's say if it's a regression problem, minimize mean square error… square.
germayne: Right? So it needs some kind of loss function. So the idea here is that, what is the definition of overfeed, means that the model is just aggressively minimizing this at all costs.
germayne: is trying to learn the parameters, right? Again, a parameter is what defines your model, right? When people say parameters, now you guys know, right, when people say, hey, you know, the language model, why is it got 99 billion parameters? Okay, so when people say parameters, right, the parameter is basically the F.
germayne: Right? Basically, the function. The… the… all the things that defines the function.
germayne: Now, I want to ask you guys one question before I continue.
germayne: We so far learned about linear regression. Can you guys tell me what is the parameter that defines a linear regression? What defines a linear regression?
Lim Hung (Lanson): Explain.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: If they wire.
germayne: No. X and Y is your data.
germayne: What defines your linear regression?
germayne: the line, right? Okay, why not? What defines the line?
germayne: Do I still need your X and Y or not if I train the linear regression model? I have the line, right? So what defines the line?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Greetings.
Teng Lee LIM: gradient.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: The gradient, huh?
germayne: Exactly. Basically, you're… this one, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: So, in terms of parameter, you can see, right, the linear regression parameter is actually very little.
germayne: Right?
germayne: So the idea here, right, for regularization is you want to introduce some kind of mechanism to prevent the model from optimizing too much on the parameters.
germayne: Right, so the model is just only going to look at this, and using this is going to generate this parameter.
germayne: Right? Again, the parameter is what defines the model. You put in your X and your Y,
germayne: you get the betas. What this means is that now, with the beta, you can make any future prediction. You no longer need your X and Ys.
germayne: Correct? You already have your… you already have your line ready. So this will apply the same for all your future models. There are going to be some kind of parameter. So now, let me ask you guys another question. What about your K&N?
germayne: What's your parameter?
germayne: What defines the K&N?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Minimum distance.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: I mean, let's…
germayne: No, that, okay, actually, not wrong wordsola. But that's not your parameter, that are the input for you to make the inference later. But what defines the KAN, what does KAN need to make the prediction?
germayne: What else?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: points.
germayne: Exactly. So for KNN, specifically for KNN, it needs to store all your X and Y.
germayne: Correct? Because it's basically just plotting your neighbor, and then… so it needs to know where your neighbor are, so actually it needs to store your X's and Y. But for your linear regression, it doesn't need… it just needs your beta value.
germayne: So for regularization, It's just a method, right, where we want to put in something to your loss function.
germayne: to tell the model that, hey man, your goal shouldn't be just to minimize your X and Y. I'm going to give you some kind of a constraint.
germayne: Right? I don't want my beta 0, beta 1, again, this is in a linear regression context. I don't want my betas
germayne: to be…
germayne: to be overfitted. I don't want it to be like, whoa, man, you minimize this thing until, like, almost close to zero, but my… my betas are, like, nonsense, right? And then in your neural network is basically all your weights. You basically have your weights lah. Basically, this is just W, right? I just defined it as W, right? Essentially, it's the same idea. So for your neural networks later.
germayne: you will see that it's actually defined by W. And of course, W is going to be very big here lah. I'm just simplifying it, but W is just a width.
germayne: Right.
germayne: Okay, so back to here, you can see here, basically, we're just going to add something to the cost function, and what we are going to do is we are going to introduce two extensions, right? We are going to… we are going to… this is actually applied to, generally.
germayne: Any… any model that minimizes mean square error.
germayne: Okay? But in linear regression.
germayne: this can be applied to linear regression first. For now, we talk about it in the context of linear regression, because I just told you that linear regression has MSE, right?
germayne: So there's two types of regularization. Typically, we call them the L1 and L2 norm. Basically, we call them the L1 norm.
germayne: By right, we are supposed to go through the normalization with you guys, but I think it's okay.
germayne: Right? The idea here is that the L1 and L2 norm, right, basically is just a mechanism for us to make some kind of restriction to prevent the model from getting too happy to minimize the function, the MSE. Because the goal is to always minimize these, right? Has a… if you guys remember in optimization class, there's always this thing, right, minimize.
germayne: this.
germayne: Which means, right.
germayne: If I can find some parameter that gives me the lowest error, the user will be happy. I'm going to do that.
germayne: But, notice, right, we are adding something here, we are adding something on the right-hand side.
germayne: And if you look at the… not to be confused, there's a W here, but the W is basically the parameters of the model. So in the case of the linear regression, the W here is basically going to be your beta.
germayne: Right, in the case of linear regression. So, in Lasso, right, what it basically means is that I'm going to add in the parameters, I'm going to add in the parameters, I'm going to add in the parameters that define my linear regression here.
germayne: along with my mean square error, with another parameter alpha. So basically, this alpha is the strength of the regularization. How much do you want to regularize?
germayne: Now, I give you guys an intuition. If alpha equals to zero, what does this mean?
germayne: What happens when alpha equals to 0?
germayne: Basically, just go back to mean square error, right? So think of it as alpha has… your lever.
germayne: for you to control how strong the regularization is, or how strong the regularization should be. If I set alpha to be 0, right, basically this whole term is gone. Basically, no regularization, right?
germayne: Alpha, I can go from 0 to infinity, usually.
germayne: So, it's a parameter that you need to tweak later on, and we'll talk about tweaking parameters later.
germayne: So the idea here, right, is that I'm adding my parameter here, telling the regression model that, okay, now you need to minimize everything.
germayne: So what does this mean?
germayne: This means that now, right, if I'm a linear regression for lasso, right, because in this function, I'm going to show the mathematical proof later on. Today, you guys will not appreciate it. We will only appreciate it after you guys unlock lesson 3.7. But the idea here is mathematically, right, if I'm putting my beta, here's my beta, the W represents beta.
germayne: If I'm putting the beta on my mean square error, basically I'm telling the model that
germayne: I'm going to ask you guys a question.
germayne: What value would better be, right, in order to make the loss function small?
germayne: So my question is, the goal for the linear regression is to make the loss function very small, right? Now, right, instead of asking him to do a mean square error, I'm going to put the parameters of the model itself, which is the beta.
germayne: I'm going to put the beta… W is basically beta lah, okay, the weights, the parameter. I'm going to put the beta along with the mean square arrow. So, as it's training, right, it's actually looking at the beta as well.
germayne: So, can I ask you guys a question? In what scenario will be the best for the loss function? Basically, beta equals to 0, right?
germayne: Hey bud, can I ask you guys a question? What does beta equals to 0 mean?
Teng Lee LIM: line.
germayne: Basically means that my dev variable is getting dropped, you know?
germayne: Right? If my linear regression model is y equals to beta 0 plus beta 1x plus beta 2X2, if any of the beta is equal to 0, I'm cancelling it out, you know?
germayne: Can you see the intuition, right?
germayne: And if I'm cancelling out this variable, what will happen? The model becomes simpler.
germayne: So, now what is happening for Lasso, right, is that you're telling the model that, amen.
germayne: I need to minimize mean square error, but at the same time, I cannot
germayne: I cannot blow up my coefficients.
germayne: And what will happen is that Lasso actually will lead to a very sparse model, which means that some of the betas will actually be zero. It will actually remove the… some of the betas.
germayne: So what we are trying to do is we're actually forcing the model to drop variables.
germayne: Does that make sense, from an intuition standpoint? If you fit a model with 77 variable, it's going to overfit for sure, because some of the variables doesn't… not going to be helpful. So if you're going to use Lasso, right, it will now force… find a way where, hey, man, if, like, I can drop from 77, I can drop to 7, I can remove 70,
germayne: I'm definitely going to improve my loss function.
germayne: So that's the ideal.
germayne: for L1 node.
germayne: Okay, that's the intuition, huh? So basically, you're forcing some kind of constraint to affect your final model parameters. Now, for… for L2, right, basically, you can see it's just a square. And today, you cannot see this, we will see this when we prove the math, but the idea is, for L2, right.
germayne: Compared to L1, L2 not so aggressive. L2 doesn't want the model to remove it. Instead, the model will try to make W1 as small as possible, which is the beta width. So now it has an incentive to make the beta values to be, you know, near zero, but not totally zero.
germayne: But lasso will actually make it zero, so that's the difference.
germayne: Okay, so the goal of doing this is that, essentially, it will help to make sure that your model is not too overfitted.
germayne: And, of course, we can apply these back to deep learning later on.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: And of course.
germayne: you know, both of them actually uses mean square error, I already talked about this. Laws function, we already talked about this, right? So basically, if you look at it, I told you guys that Module 3 is actually a lot of math.
germayne: If you are very comfortable with math, you just go back and, oh, I can go and differentiate this. I can tell you guys a lot of things will be very easy.
germayne: Right.
germayne: From a math perspective. But the idea here is that if you don't want to know the math, the idea here is I just want to reduce this, and intuition-wise, for lasso.
germayne: The model has an incentive to zero out some of the coefficients, so that
germayne: I might have a simpler model. Same thing for L2. I want to reduce W1 to be as tiny as possible, but not 0.
germayne: And of course, you can combine all of them together, right? So if you see the mathematical here, here we are combining the… so basically, this is the lasso.
germayne: Plus, this is the… the reach.
germayne: Right? And then, basically, we have some parameters here, where we have alpha, and we have rho.
germayne: So basically, right, you will see, right, hey, why got so many parameters? You, as a user, is supposed to decide what these parameters are.
germayne: Okay? And later on, I'm going to tell you guys more about the parameters. So now you realize, there's more and more things added on, and it's not like everybody will have the same results. That means,
germayne: You'll notice that there's so many factors that's different already.
germayne: How you process the data is different. How you choose the data is different. What kind of model you choose is going to be different from everyone else. What kind of parameters you choose from your model is going to be different.
germayne: So you guys can start to see the degree of freedom to train models is going to be very different, right? So not… not one single person will have the exact same thing, which is why I told you guys that you start to realize that this is not… not that simple.
germayne: Okay, I'm going to pause here first, but does anybody has any question for me for the intuition of this?
germayne: Okay, from a code perspective, what will happen is that now that there's regularization, sklearn actually has some library to do reach regression and lasso regression.
germayne: So basically, if you were to just import the reach regression, you will find out that there will be a parameter for you to tune for this. If you put for lasso, same thing. And of course, you also can do one for ElasticNet.
germayne: Right? So basically, these models, because there's an additional parameter to safeguard your model from overfitting.
germayne: it will actually be better in generalizing. In general, regularized models should always be better. Okay, of course, there's a lot of factors lah. If your data set is already not done correctly, then obviously how you regularize doesn't help, because
germayne: Why? Can somebody answer? Answer? If in the first place you are not using enough data, you're not using the correct data, why would regularization not help?
germayne: I'm gonna give you guys the hint.
germayne: link back to bias variants. So why?
germayne: So why would, you know, if your model is not good enough.
germayne: Why is it that regularization doesn't help? Because I just made a statement that, hey, in general, regularization is actually a good thing.
germayne: But why?
germayne: Anybody knows.
Zac Ang: It will still be very biased.
germayne: Exactly, because you are high buyers, you're underfitting.
germayne: So this only works, right, when you're… when you are in the realm of high variance, which means you're actually fitting the model quite well, but you're starting to overfit a bit, and you realize that you need to drop stuff.
germayne: How do you drop stuff? You ask the model to do it by putting it in the loss function. And of course, you are supposed to define how much of the penalty to do. And of course, if you guys can see mathematically, if you put the penalty here and the penalty here to be very big, right, obviously the impact on making the mistake becomes more sensitive.
germayne: If the weight on alpha and rho is very high, then the model will take a lot of attention to make sure that these two terms are not very high.
germayne: So you guys realize, right, the model is just like a baby. The model doesn't know anything. You are the one in control. You're the one to decide what is the direction of training the model.
germayne: Okay, before we go on to the next concept, this is to emphasize what I just mentioned, and we'll talk about the cross-validation, which is the thing that will relate back to how do you test your metric.
germayne: Anybody has any questions for me before I move on from regularization?
germayne: Yes, yes, Zach.
Zac Ang: Oh, we've been talking about, just…
Zac Ang: the normal linear type of regression, right? Like, we didn't… all of this is… doesn't really apply for non-linear kind of regression.
germayne: No, no, no, this applies. I wrote here.
germayne: We will come back to this, don't worry.
Zac Ang: Okay.
germayne: So this applies to deep learning as well. The math is the same. Exact same math.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So the math here, the takeaway, right, if you go for interview… okay, I shouldn't keep saying that, but in terms of, like, understanding this, if, let's say, the takeaway from L1 is to reduce the parameters to 0 and reach… to make the parameters smaller, it applies to every single model that uses this.
germayne: Okay, and deep learning actually is one model that uses. So it's not like, oh, this is only linear regression.
germayne: Okay? Anybody got any last question before I go?
germayne: Okay, not too, not too fast, huh? Anybody need any question?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I don't want to raise my question.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Hello, Mike.
germayne: You take your time to think, don't have to ask now. If you think over it, then we can discuss that.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so, just like what I mentioned, if you look at this AI-generated diagram, there's this thing called parameters. I already mentioned what parameters means to you. So, when you train a model.
germayne: What you get, right, is the parameter.
germayne: is what defines the model. If you want to think about a model as an entity, it is this thing that is very important. There's a lot of terms for this, people call it parameters, people call it weights.
germayne: is alias, basically, it's a synonym, right? So now, whenever people say that, oh, you know, I'm releasing the next new LAMA weights, I'm releasing the next quen weights, when people talk about AI models, right? They're talking about parameter. Essentially, if I have the weights, I have access to the train model.
germayne: Right? So it's what defines the model, right? That's the parameter.
germayne: No.
germayne: what are the inputs to your model? It's basically your data.
germayne: Your data is your X, your Y.
germayne: And you start to realize that each of the models, you're going to make some decision. Of course, from the data perspective, it's your pre-processing.
germayne: Right? But apart from that.
germayne: each of your models, right? Think of it like they are some kind of engine, you know? The models that we introduced to you, think of them like some kind of vehicle. When you're operating the vehicle, there's a lot of things that you're supposed to control, right? And these are what we call the hyperparameters.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Of course, for linear regression, not too much hyperparameter.
germayne: Right? Your KNN, of course, have hyperparameters. Anybody wants to tell me what are some of the hyperparameters for KNN?
germayne: Just not what you guys mentioned, right?
germayne: the distance.
germayne: What else?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: About neighbors.
germayne: The number of neighbors, exactly. So you guys get the, get the G's now.
germayne: Right? Basically, right, these are the things that, hey, shit, actually, I need to decide.
germayne: And these parameters will affect your… sorry, these hyperparameters will affect your parameters. And of course, right, the more model I introduce, right, the more knobs you have now. Think of them as, like, the control knobs. Oh, there's just a lot, you know? You need to be able to tune them from a hyperparameter standpoint.
germayne: Okay? And just now, when we introduced, reach, the regularization, you have alpha, you have rho.
germayne: Right? If you are… if you are doing specifically lasso or ridge regression.
germayne: But different models have different parameters to regularize.
germayne: Okay? So basically, think of it like your engine, and you're supposed to be the one to tune it.
germayne: Okay, but of course, in reality, there's so many. Some models have, like, 20 over parameters.
germayne: Well, how am I gonna… how am I going to deal?
germayne: Right, so if you can see, the example alpha and rho, there are some examples of hyperparameter.
germayne: Okay, so again, right, we're going to combine the whole concept, right? So that's why I want you guys to understand, not so much from the code, but from a concept standpoint, that your model has hyperparameter. How do you know which hyperparameter is correct? You're going to use a method called validation.
germayne: how are you going to use the validation? You're going to think about a selection of a metric.
germayne: That best describes your situation.
germayne: And you're going to use this metric to design a validation method.
germayne: And if you think about it, right, what is the… what is the brute force mechanism to try? If I have 20 parameters.
germayne: Essentially, I have, like, a whole combin- I have, like, what? A lot of combination, man. It's not possible for me to try. 20 parameters is not just 20 combinations, I have so many combinations to tweak.
germayne: So…
germayne: If, let's say, hypothetically, you can hire a monkey, you just ask the monkey to try every combination, right? Try every… every complete combination until you get it. But do you guys think it's possible?
germayne: It's not possible.
germayne: if I train a model… if one model takes 8 hours to train.
germayne: I have 20… I have 20 parameters.
germayne: Essentially, I have 20 permutations here, you know, like, 20 factorial. How am I… how am I possible… it's not possible for me to try out, right?
germayne: So I, you know, you know, is there some way that we can do it?
germayne: But I can tell you guys the good news.
germayne: The good news is that, in reality, hyperparameter tuning is actually not as important as you think it is.
germayne: It's not that important.
germayne: You can… if you are experienced enough, you can tweak it a bit. That's it. You don't always need to find the most optimal parameters.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, I want to spend some time talking about validation.
germayne: Okay, the… the whole idea, right, let me… okay, wait, let me… let me see if I can take a blank canvas.
germayne: payoff.
germayne: I'm going to spend some time talking about validation, because this is super, super important.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Now, right, so far, if you guys realize, conceptually, we are always taking some data set, this is your dataset X,
germayne: And you have some kind of corresponding Y data.
germayne: You realize that we're always taking this… oh, okay, actually, this is a wrong illustration.
germayne: the Y should be equally long.
germayne: You guys realize, that when we train a model, these are actually the two basic ingredients. Of course, we have all the hyperparameters and whatever lah, that we introduce.
germayne: But we don't talk about them first. But you realize that this is actually the basic ingredient
germayne: to put into your machine learning model. Imagine, like, you put into your model.
germayne: And then your model is trained.
germayne: Now the question is, how do you know whether your model works?
germayne: And actually, if you think about it, right, conceptually, the idea is actually not… not very counterintuitive. It's actually very, very intuitive. The idea is that I should always be designing a way, right, to test my data. If today, right, you guys actually created an investment
germayne: System to do investment.
germayne: What is the best way to test it?
germayne: So go and do some backtests, right? Right? If you are so sure that your investment can make money.
germayne: there's two ways to test it. You either deploy it and do it right now, from 16th April onwards.
germayne: Or, you can actually do it with some kind of cut-off data.
germayne: So the idea is actually very simple. You have some kind of data, can I actually take a bid out?
germayne: Can I actually cut a bit of data out?
germayne: so that I can actually Use it to test the model.
germayne: Right? So far, intuition makes sense, right?
germayne: Correct?
germayne: So the idea is that… and okay, maybe one question to you guys, why do I need to cut it out?
germayne: can't I just train the model, and then I just test it on everything?
germayne: So let me ask again, so instead of cutting.
germayne: Can someone tell me what's wrong with this? I train the model, I just… I just test on everything here lah.
germayne: Well, why can't I do that?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Your model has seen everything already.
germayne: So… so what's wrong with it? What's wrong with the model seeing everything already?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Then your test will turn out.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Correct, in a sense.
germayne: exactly, exactly.
germayne: Correct? Because the intuition is that if I studied the 10-year series, or, like, the… I practiced some kind of exam paper, I do the same exam paper, it's not a good way to gauge, right? You… you… the intuition feels like something is wrong, right? You might get a result that's very good, but you're just probably bluffing yourself. So the whole idea here is that, okay.
germayne: Now, if I know that I want to isolate something, then I just want to cut something out, right?
germayne: I'm just going to cut something out, and what will happen is that I'm going to cut something out so that when I expose my model.
germayne: I'm only going to use a portion of it.
germayne: Correct. And the remaining one, I would just want to use a portion that are intentionally excluded.
germayne: Correct? That's a… that's a whole central idea. Now.
germayne: What we want to expand on is there's many ways you can do this cutting of the cake.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: What do you guys think is the simplest?
germayne: What's, what's the easiest?
Josiah Ho: 5060.
germayne: So basically you just split lah, right? And that's the function that you guys saw, trim test split.
germayne: You can basically set, like, well, whatever you want. You can set 50, you can set 70, you can set 30. But the idea is, Josiah, if I set 50-50, right, what's the drawback?
germayne: Like, what's the drawback of setting 50-50?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Not enough to train and test.
germayne: Correct. So the more you take out means your training gets less, mah.
germayne: Correct. So, of course, you see all the toy data, they just take 0.3 lah. Here, I take 30%.
germayne: Here, I take 30%.
germayne: Yeah, I take 70% but then, I can tell you that there's no rule of thumb, it depends.
germayne: if you tell me today your data 1 million versus 300K, maybe debatable lah, right? Doesn't really matter, that one you decide.
germayne: Correct? But the idea, right, is
germayne: Today, right, I'm not going to tell you guys how to cut it. Instead, I'm going to tell you guys how to think about cutting this.
germayne: Okay, so of course, at very basic.
germayne: I'm just going to randomly select 30% out, which is the exact same function that you guys saw. And then now you guys ask me why I got the seat. Now you guys know why there's a seed, right? Because I'm taking 30% randomly. If I want to replicate and ensure that the whole class can cut the same 30%, I set a seat, so that everybody cuts the same 30% pie out.
germayne: So that's the basic idea. But can we expand this idea to make it more complex?
germayne: We can.
germayne: And that is… that's actually the next step. So, we can do something called KFO.
germayne: Okay? So K4, the idea, very simple. Same concept, same story again.
germayne: You have 1 pi, X, And wife?
germayne: Now, the idea is that you feel that, hey, maybe if I cut 30%, the intuition is that if I cut… if I cut, let's say, 20% here.
germayne: Could it be that I might be lucky that I cut off the one that I can predict well?
germayne: You know, you think of that idea, right? You know, maybe if I, if I, if I, if I, if I cut just 20%, right, whoa.
germayne: how do I know whether by these 20% robbers? What if I'm just lucky?
germayne: And then the idea is maybe I can cut a different 20%,
germayne: So what you can do is you can just cut another 20%, right?
germayne: And I want to do it without reducing my training data. Of course you can do it, right? So then you cut a different portion.
Josiah Ho: Do you mean? The screen is not moving.
germayne: No, because I, I, I, I, I haven't read.
Josiah Ho: Oh.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
germayne: Is he?
germayne: Is it… is it okay?
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah. My iPad got, like, some area cannot write, I also don't know why. Okay, but…
germayne: The first 4, right, you cut the 20% at the back, can I just cut the 20% here?
germayne: Right? So essentially, for the first one, I'm using, like that.
germayne: Okay, I removed the Y lah, okay, you guys don't need the Y, right? I don't have to draw this twice.
germayne: The X and the Y is the same.
germayne: But the idea is, for the second cut, right, can I just cut the middle? And I just use this,
germayne: Right? And what if for the next one I do the same?
germayne: And then how many, then, you guys, how many, how many times can I do this?
germayne: Bye, bye.
germayne: Five times, right? Because I take 20%.
germayne: So what is this? This is actually quite robust, right? Means that I can actually get an average of 5 evaluations.
germayne: And I can actually use up the full dataset that I have without actually exposing the dataset, because what I'm precisely doing is exactly what I want to test it, right? I'm cutting enough so that my model don't get exposed to it. You realize each of the cuts that you are doing.
germayne: it has not seen that 20%, and you can do this 5 times. And you can choose the K, because K is a parameter, you can choose
germayne: How many foes you want.
germayne: Right? Of course, the trade-off is that you need to make sure that your test data is enough lah, your validation data is enough.
germayne: Okay, so that's the concept of KFO.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I got a question.
germayne: Yes.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, let's say we are talking about linear regression, right? You've got X and Y. So for every X, like, you know, I mean, it's an equation, right? But every X has a Y. So when I cut the X, right, I must make sure that the appropriate Y is also cut, right?
germayne: Yes, yes, yes, yes, you must cut the same… yes, you… so what I'm… what I'm drawing here assumes you cut the same row. You cut row by row, so every corresponding row has a corresponding Y. Yes, you cut… you cut every row.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, yeah, yeah, no.
germayne: No, no, yes, yes, yes,
germayne: That's why I said, right, if you cannot cut right, you can use the library to cut. But then, actually, you realize that cutting this manually is also not very difficult, mah, agree, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You just need to know that, is she okay?
germayne: You just need to keep track of your index. If I have an index from 0 to n, right, I just keep track of my index lah. That's not my point, is that the library is not important. The library will help you do it easily, but without the library, it's not like you cannot do it.
germayne: Right? And a lot of people actually do K4 manually. I do K4 manually.
germayne: for different reasons, because I want to control what I can do inside the fold, right? I have more complex mechanisms that I want to do transformation without within the fold. But if you don't have very complex stuff, you just use the K4 scikit-learn to do it. They can do it for you, they'll cut it for you.
germayne: Oh, Hida, I asked you guys a question.
germayne: If I were to do this 5 times in this example, do I actually have 5 models?
germayne: What do you guys think?
germayne: Do I have 5 different models, actually?
germayne: Pretty curious, huh?
germayne: I fight even more narrow, right Sticking with it.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Can one data set have more than one model? Because it's like…
germayne: Yeah, correct.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, excellent.
germayne: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I was thinking this when I was doing my pre-study, I was like,
germayne: Correct, correct.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Maybe if, yeah, I know, like, more than one model for one data set, why not, right?
germayne: Correct.
germayne: So the… so what happens is that scikit-learn, right, they actually do store the… if I remember correctly, it's been a while since I used scikit-learn, to be honest.
germayne: They do store the model that gives the best performance, but typically, typically what people usually do, right, another method is you either take the best model out of the five.
germayne: Or, what do you guys think is another alternative?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Which you don't.
germayne: Huh?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: average it out.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: every shot, I said.
germayne: No, you cannot average the model no, so you can keep… you can actually, okay, so there's… actually, there's also valid. So there are people that keep the 5 model, then they make a prediction, then they average the prediction, but you cannot average the model.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yellow, that's how you may not.
germayne: Correct, correct. So, but that one, you have to maintain fine model, not scalable
germayne: So, so typically, okay, so there's actually many mechanisms. There's no right or wrong answer. You take the best.
germayne: That's one option.
germayne: You keep all five.
germayne: And then you make 5 predictions, but you can see it's a lot of work, well, I need to maintain 5 models.
germayne: Or, one idea that a lot of people also do is, you now retrain the model on the full dataset.
germayne: Why waste the 20%? I can train on everything. Once you have evaluated, you can train the full model on your data, right?
germayne: you have enough evidence that the model should be good across 5 cuts. So that's what people do.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But will this not be overfitting?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: We're starting to be everything already.
germayne: Noah, you won't overfita?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Why, why not?
germayne: Okay, why not I ask you why would you think you overfit?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because you see all the data, I mean, let's say you do one bit of cut into 5 pieces, for example, then…
germayne: Yeah, now you do…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, good.
germayne: Go point, good point.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: all the, all the data right there, I see everything.
germayne: Good point, good point. But let me ask you lah, when I train this model, what's the purpose of this model for? Is it to predict anything within the cut here?
germayne: Or is it to predict something in the future?
germayne: It's for the… it's for the future, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, okay.
germayne: It's for the future, right?
germayne: So why, why, why we overfeed? It won't overfeed.
germayne: assuming you do everything correctly lah, more data doesn't mean overfeed. Okay, that's a dangerous misconception, huh? If, let's.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah, precisely, that's all.
germayne: Yeah, correct. So if, let's say, your thought process here is, well, more data means overfeed, then that's a wrong takeaway already. That's wrong already.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I guess you know that.
germayne: Okay, huh?
germayne: Okay? All clear. All clear conceptually for K4, because we are going to go, we are going to make this more complex. You guys ready?
germayne: Okay, so just now, soon mention something about Stratified.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Sorry, Jeremy, before we proceed, actually, just want to say careful, and then some people also thinking.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Why they don't want to take the whole set data?
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, yeah, because it's very troublesome in to pick out the best one.
germayne: -
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah.
Chieh Cheng Lai: thinking reverse. People were thinking reverse way back again, training the whole, the whole data.
germayne: Oh, so you're asking why people do this, is it?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, yeah, yeah, reverse.
germayne: The intuition is very simple, because the 5 data have not been using 100% of the data.
germayne: The 5 model here is all missing a piece, what, right?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yes.
germayne: So the answer to your question is, why would people consider this? It's because this uses the full data set.
germayne: I have a model that uses everything, don't waste lah. That's the idea.
Chieh Cheng Lai: This is…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Interesting.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Initially, because, we are… we tried to move to the K4 is because, for… for the whole data set, which means that, it's… it's the original idea, that… that's why people moved to K4. Then after that, from K4, moved back to the whole data set.
germayne: This is what I call.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Excuse me.
germayne: No, no, you don't… you don't move back. After… okay, so, okay, so again, let's take a step back to answer this question. Why we do K4 first?
germayne: We do careful because we want to validate.
germayne: If the model that you have, the dataset, whatever, is working.
germayne: Once you validate already, right, what's the next step? The next step is usually your model is to make prediction on something else.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yes.
germayne: Correct? That's what you want to use it for.
germayne: Let me give you guys an example, okay? Let's start with a very simple example. So, in your Kaggle data set, right, your Kegel.
germayne: I will be giving you guys a training data.
germayne: And for the sake of the competition, right, I'll be giving you guys the test data.
germayne: This test data, right, will not have Y.
germayne: So there's no wire, this test data that I give you guys. So…
germayne: What will happen is that you guys, right, in the leaderboard, right, it will be… it will split 30-70 here.
germayne: Right?
germayne: This one will be the public.
germayne: This one will be the private.
germayne: And take note, your test data set, right? There's no why. Basically, you guys don't have the answer, only I have the answer.
germayne: Right?
germayne: What will happen is that at the end of the… nearing the end of the course, right, we will… we will review the full data set.
germayne: And we will see which group gets the top.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: Now, from your perspective, back to the training. Training, here you got your X and Y.
germayne: Now, when we introduce a concept, why do you want to do the validation? Because
germayne: you guys start to realize that I have a lot of decisions to make. I can… I need to do this, I need to drop this, I need to preprocess, I need to fill this, I need to scale the data, I need to choose ELGO1. After I choose ELGO1, I need to tweak the algo… I… basically, right, all of you guys, right, have a lot of decisions to make.
germayne: How do you know whether to day right?
germayne: what changes that you guys are making is actually the correct direction. So what you want to do is you want to use your training data to do validation.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: So now we repeat again, back to the K4.
germayne: So in the HDV price, right, you use the data that you have, right, X and Y, you do K4, and you'll be like, hey, actually, these guys, we are doing well. This is correct, this is a good direction. Your model is good.
germayne: But then, right, if you want to submit your data for the test, right, you want to make the prediction, you want to predict here.
germayne: Is it wrong for me to say that, hey, let's train on 100% of the data on the changes that we have to predict the 30 and the 70? Not wrong, right?
germayne: So now you guys get the idea?
germayne: You can also use the 80%, and you can also use one of it, not wrong, it's not that it's wrong, but some people will be like, okay, I don't want to waste the 20%.
germayne: I'd rather, like, okay, let's just use everything. Maybe, who knows? Maybe having everything will be better. You know, you will never know.
germayne: You get what I mean?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, I understand already. Yeah, because in the trend, you get the decision. After that, you just put this parameter, relevant parameter, you think, and to the test.
germayne: Yep.
germayne: Yeah, yeah. Okay, I think somebody else got one more… one question, right? Yeah, Teng Li, yeah.
Teng Lee LIM: No, because I was saying that, but if you were to use the whole data to train again, then you would get a new model again.
germayne: a new… yes, a new model, but assuming you… you don't change too much, like, you don't change… basically, there are some decisions that you make, you get enough validation from your… from your validation data, you just do… you just stick with the same thing and train the model. That's what people do also. Yes, the model will be different.
germayne: But models shouldn't be too sensitive that
germayne: Because if your model is so bad, right, that you put the full data, that means you are in the same concept as
germayne: Overfitting, you know, where if you change the data, then your model change.
germayne: Assuming that your model is really correct, right, it shouldn't be that drastic.
germayne: That's the intuition.
germayne: Make sense?
Teng Lee LIM: J.
Teng Lee LIM: Makes sense, but because it's… because of the hyperparameter, we don't… we'll use… hepatitis.
germayne: Good, good, good question, good question, good question. Yes. In this case, because you cannot validate, right, you use whatever that you have optimized in this K4, then you do it for the test.
Teng Lee LIM: Okay.
germayne: But I will let you guys try this out. I mean, that's the whole point, right? You guys will try it out. You guys have the opportunity to try it out, and tell me what works.
germayne: Because in real life, it's this difficult. You cannot find the best parameters for your real life, right? When you go to production, let's say today, right? Okay, and I'm going… what I want to do is I just replace… let's use the same analogy. We're going to do the same thing. Let's say you are in the HDB team.
germayne: You train the model.
germayne: And then you say, like, okay, very fantastic, good, ready to go. When you go live on 17th April, right, you are doing the same, right? It's unknown territory already.
germayne: You get what I mean? So, the whole point I want to emphasize with you guys is that the validation process is super, super, super critical, because if your validation, right, you can imagine if your validation is wrong, right?
germayne: then you're just going to go blind into the real world, which is, like, here. Your here is, like, wrong.
germayne: But if your validation is done perfectly, right? No, there's no problem going to the real life.
germayne: Right? In fact, right, in fact, now I'm also… I'm going to expand on two standards. In fact, the gold standard, right.
germayne: I'm going to share with you guys this industry gold standard. Gold standard, right, actually, is you've got your data set,
germayne: Of course, if you have no data, then you cannot do this life. If you are poor on data, then you have to do whatever you can. But in real life.
germayne: what I love to do is…
germayne: this is the time axis. I like to take something in the future. I like to cut something in the future. So I would… I'll probably take, like, something like, this is the last 3 months. Again, this is an example.
germayne: Last 3 months, I will segregate maybe 1 week worth of data for the future.
germayne: And why do I want to do that? Because I want to create an environment where my validation, my validation.
germayne: Simulates as much as possible of going live.
germayne: And what's the best way to test when going live? Is to make a prediction into the future. That's the best way to test when it's going live, right?
germayne: Because if my model is going to be live for one week, I need to make sure that it's able to forecast in the next one week's worth of data. How do I do that? Exactly the same thing I told you guys for the… you know, you guys were saying that, okay, I want to do some financial modeling or whatever. The best way is to do backtesting, and how do you backtest?
germayne: if I'm going to deploy my model today, my model will only have access with whatever data up till today's date. You're always going to make a prediction in the future, right? So the best gold standard is actually have your own test.
germayne: in the future. And you can do whatever strategy you want to do K4 or whatever, and it's what we call validate.
germayne: So there's actually two mechanisms here. I'm actually doing validation.
germayne: Here, you can do K4, You can do a split.
germayne: Etc, doesn't matter.
germayne: After I've done validation, I'll do one final test, where it's a final test.
germayne: And here, I will still have my Y value, right? I'll do one more test.
germayne: And the idea here is that I want to make sure that I'm not biased by the validation feedback loop. Because actually the validation here is a bit biased because you might still be optimizing some parameters during validation process, so the validation is still the best case scenario.
germayne: So I'll still do one more test to test in the future. So, a very good analogy is, you know, sometimes if you are in junior college, or if you are in… I'm not sure about your O levels, sometimes the school will do preliminary 2, like, prelim too, like, there's another prelim.
germayne: Right? So the intuition is like that, like, you validate already, you do one more, one final one, and the idea is this test, right, is not supposed to have any feedback loop here. So I will not be using this test set, right, to go and, like, oh my god, let's make sure the test set works. You cannot do that, because if you do that, right.
germayne: your test data and your validation data is the same, right? You're using it to optimize your data. So what you need to do, right, the gold standard is that actually you have one test, right, that is, like.
germayne: You know, you sort of, like, really just keep it
germayne: It's like your stash. You just keep it so that before you go live or what, you use to test it to see whether okay or not. If not okay, right?
germayne: You go back and fix within this ecosystem. You don't use that, you don't use this test set.
germayne: But you start to realize, actually, it's very similar to Kaggle, right? It's actually very, very similar.
germayne: you guys will have exposure to the 30% of data in your leaderboard. Which means, today, let's say, Zach's team, he uploaded the model. Oh my god, they are taught!
germayne: But they are actually looking at 30% of the data, right?
germayne: They can do validation also, you can do your own validation here, you can cut your 20% here. Because why? I'm going to limit every team to only
germayne: Upload the dataset 5 times a day.
germayne: So you can only see your 30% score, right, only 5 times per day. So what this means is that you need to think of a way to do this ecosystem, because you're going to try a million of stuff, you guys got, like, 5 people in the team, you guys are going to try a lot of stuff.
germayne: there's no way you can finish the upload. But then maybe at the end of the day.
germayne: If you're 20% or you're K4, right.
germayne: actually matches the 30%, then I don't really need to keep uploading to check the 30%, if you think about what I mean.
germayne: Right? I have a strategy that I can always check internally.
germayne: But then the true test is actually the 70%, that's the true test, to test whether your model overfeits, because there are cases, right, last time in the past where I competed in Kaggle, there were people, like, at the top of the leaderboard for, like, the first 3 months, right? Then when the final release, right, they dropped all the way to, like, 1,000 position.
germayne: Which means that the model is not correct, right? They overfit so much to the 30% that actually it's not wrong, it's not the correct model, so…
germayne: Principally, if you think about it, right, what I'm trying to tell you guys is that
germayne: From a design perspective, right, the bottom line is you want to emulate as much as possible what you are trying to achieve.
germayne: The reason I chose one week is because I expect my model to be retrained every week, on a weekly basis, automatically, right? So that means the model is going to be refreshed every week. So that means that my model will always be tested one week in the future. So I want to test this one week in the future, but of course, I also have my own validation data, which is the one I talk about here.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: All good, right? I would say Kaggle will be a very, very good place to practice this concept, and validation is super, super important.
germayne: Now you guys know why the metric is important, right? The metric is important because choosing the right metric matters. In Kagger's case, of course, it doesn't matter. Kager's case, I already choose RMSE, so you guys would just use RMSE, doesn't matter, but in real life, it matters. And in real life, you will be the one to design this decision because
germayne: You need to design a model that you have confidence to test it.
germayne: So if, let's say, right, you hypothetically have a trading model that can predict one way in advance and get you, like, X amount of money, please don't go and tell anyone, you just use it yourself.
germayne: Right? But that would be a good test, right? If your model can, like, survive one week.
germayne: by accounting for one week in the future, if let's say, tomorrow Trump say something weird again, market crash, and somehow your model can handle that, that would be a true test, right?
germayne: Because if your model can't even handle this stochastic event, then your model is not truly good in
germayne: Investing, if you know what I mean.
germayne: Which is why people say trading model is very, very hard, because the signal is just very noisy.
germayne: Okay? Understand that?
germayne: Any questions or not, so far?
germayne: Good, huh? Okay, so I feel like Kaggle would be a very good way to understand this concept. Do Kaggle already, then we discuss again.
germayne: Okay, last thing, just want to wrap up what Sue mentioned, so…
germayne: We talk a lot about splitting the data, right?
germayne: The… the only thing we never talk about is that in… in classification problem, in classification problem.
germayne: The distribution of the data matters.
germayne: the distribution of the data matters, right? We talked about yesterday, like, oh, you know, if you have very high ones and zeros, it matters.
germayne: So if, let's say, your distribution is like that, right, what do you think is the good way to split the data? You want to ensure that the distribution of the data that you split also maintains the same
germayne: The same as you train, correct?
germayne: That's the idea, right? So if, no matter how I split, I do K4,
germayne: I do, split, train, test, split, train, test, split.
germayne: I want to make sure that if I'm… if it's a classification, I want to make sure that the distribution is maintained. If my 1 is this high, I want to make sure my 1 is also this high.
germayne: Okay? But let me ask you guys a question.
germayne: Is testing this foolproof or not?
germayne: does this always… does this matter? Okay, sorry. The question will be, is this a foolproof mechanism? Is it like Jermaine says that… Jermaine and soon says that, okay, classification always do stratified?
germayne: Is it a true statement?
Zac Ang: Depends on what you're trying to achieve.
germayne: I think you… I think you get the pattern of what I'm always asking, correct? But why, why?
Teng Lee LIM: I think this… is it because, like, the real-world data distribution might not be what you're…
germayne: As a, as a, as a.
Teng Lee LIM: What you have lah.
germayne: Exactly. So, you guys got the G's already.
germayne: Okay, so the concept here is that you want to make sure the distribution is the same, because what you train, right.
germayne: what you train and what you validate. I call it the validate lah, okay? Because this is always within your environment. What you train and what you validate, right? If the distribution is perfectly the same, it's good. Because whatever you train, you will predict properly. But the only hidden gap here is that you do not know what is the distribution here.
germayne: If, let's say, hypothetically, you know that the distribution will be the same, you have no reason to feel like the distribution wouldn't change, then this would be the strategy. But if you have some kind of strong rationale that, okay, my data is very biased, maybe the distribution would change, then you might not want to specifically stratify.
germayne: Okay? Because you want to test out the difference in distribution.
germayne: Okay? And basically, for stratified, right, the equivalent library is just called Stratified KFO. Basically, you just put the… you just use stratified KFO, it will guarantee that every…
germayne: every 20%, right, the distribution will be the same. It will try to make sure that when they split out and sample, the distribution will be retained the same as your train, right? So, I think they're stratified K4, and I think in your train-test split.
germayne: I remember should be, there's a stratified option lah. I remember there should be, there's also a stratified, I think it's in the parameter, you just need to set it as stratified.
germayne: And it will ensure that there's a same distribution.
germayne: Okay, I want to really, really emphasize this to be very important. I… I can tell you guys, I trained a lot of models in production, really, and…
germayne: a lot of issues, right, comes from the fact that if you cannot design this properly.
germayne: then your… your… when you… you know, let's say when we have the POC, right, and then you go to production, you're going to get a very, very huge difference in performance, and it's going to be a bad thing, right? And… and I believe, lah, I have the right to say, because I trained very complex models, and they're all in production today, I've trained, like, a lot of real-time models.
germayne: And so far, my models, right, has been there for, like, 3-4 years already, and I do not have to touch it. Okay, not true lah. Sometimes you need to maintain, but it's quite robust. It's not like, wow, I know it's so flaky, right? It doesn't survive very extreme change in events, but…
germayne: When we do the testing, everything is perfect, it's perfect, like, there's no surprises.
germayne: Right, so I just want to emphasize this is super important, and hopefully you guys get to experience this in the Kaggle dataset.
germayne: Okay, I will switch back. But hopefully this gives the insight, I think I spent a bit of time here, because I think this is super important. This is, like, the most important…
germayne: Concept for machine learning.
germayne: Okay, so you can basically just see the graph here lah, it's exactly whatever I told you, the chart, yeah. So I'm going to skip all of this.
germayne: Okay, so back to the… back to the parameters, right? The problem with the parameters is that now that you guys realize that, oh man, well, I need to decide whether what to scale, what thing to use… Actually, all of these are sort of parameters, because
germayne: if I can change them, you can think of them as, if I change them, I can just validate, right? If I change them, I can just validate. So, in theory, which is why I said that machine learning, right, the validation strategy is very solid, because you have a way to actually test out
germayne: whether what you change matters is very different from statistical inference. If today, right, Tang Li says that, oh, she found a cure to cancer, you know, using some linear model.
germayne: well, people will still be like, are you sure, you know, your model, is it correct? But for validation, right, it's straightforward. If you design it properly, all your assumptions are met, right? You will be able to get a very immediate… I mean.
germayne: Of course, in your HDB data, just telling you guys, your dataset, I intentionally make it huge. I think there's hundreds over thousands of data.
germayne: So, it won't be so quick that you guys can get a feedback, right, if you are using a more complex model. So the idea here is that if I have a lot of combination to test out, right, well, how am I going to test it? Can I just do grid search? So grid search is basically, you define all the different ranges, and you will just train the model automatically for you, so it will take a long time.
germayne: It will take, like, a few hours, or even days, depending on how long your model is.
germayne: So, obviously, this is not… not… not great.
germayne: Random search, basically, like, they just automatically try out lah.
germayne: So if you guys learn about, optimization, actually, this is a form of optimization, and random is just like, you know, maybe, maybe let's say the idea is that I have a, I have a, I have a hue.
germayne: I have a range of hue values. I do not know at which point is the lowest, right? I can try here, I can try here, I can try here, I can try here, but the idea is, hey, maybe if I randomly try, I might find treasure, right? Instead of trying them from, like, well, one by one, one by one, one by one, one by one one by one.
germayne: I will never, ever reach… the optimal parameters. So the idea is to do random search.
germayne: Now, in reality, do people do random search and grid search?
germayne: Not really. People don't really do that. People usually use other, optimization. If you are interested, there's actually Bayesian.
germayne: They do, Bayesian optimization.
germayne: Feel free to read out on it.
germayne: Right? And people like me.
germayne: I did so much Kaggle that, actually, we also don't really use Bayesian lah, we just tune yourself. You just know what to tune, no. You just tune, make sure the model didn't overfit, then you just tune this and tune that.
germayne: Right? So, it's difficult, it's a very difficult problem, but…
germayne: in practice, if let's say you're talking about, like, in company level, I can tell you that optimization is actually not that important, because
germayne: if today, right, I have some kind of model, I just want to have some kind of performance, let's say my performance is, like, 100,
germayne: A root mean square arrow.
germayne: Right?
germayne: Tomorrow, if the model is, like, 101 or 102,
germayne: Let me ask you guys, do you think it matters? Yeah, it doesn't really matter.
germayne: it doesn't… the business is actually not going to be that sensitive to all the things, and it's not Kaggle. So only in Kaggle then we do this, because Kaggle, right.
germayne: the placing between the first, second place is, like, in the decimal place on, like, 0.81, no, 0.82. I don't really care whether my model is, like, at this decimal place, right? So, in reality.
germayne: actually, hyperparameter tuning is not that important. You still need to tweak a bit, you still need to know what to tune for, but you don't need to find the best parameter, and you don't have time to train that kind of model, because,
germayne: let's say, for example, my team, right? My team has so many models.
germayne: Some model takes, like, 1-2 hours to train.
germayne: oh man, like, can you imagine you want to find a parameter every week? Doesn't make sense, right? So we… I tuned it once, like, 4 years ago, the model's parameter, nobody has changed it up till today. The parameter has been the same.
germayne: So, this will be… but still, right, having said that, for Kaggle, I want you guys to try this out, right? You guys will still need to think, like, oh, how do I actually tune the model to make sure that the model performs better? So you guys still need to do that.
germayne: Okay, so actually, you guys start to get the whole idea of the whole workflow, right? The workflow is you do EDA,
germayne: split your data, usually you need to split your data. Then after that, you just keep this data, right? So, like what I mentioned, there's different school of thoughts.
germayne: The one that I recommend is you split into three.
germayne: Train, validation, test.
germayne: If you are doing K4, This is… this is actually your trade.
germayne: Right, then you keep… you keep one… one test.
germayne: But of course, right, if today you're telling me that your dataset only got 1,000 rows, well, then 100 or 1,000 rows, then…
germayne: or then really not enough to split, man, then you really cannot split. But if you have… if you are in the company with, like, well, you can take 3 million, like, my data set can, like, easily reach 10 to 20 million, right? Like, to me, it doesn't matter, I have the luxury to split whatever I want.
germayne: Right? So it depends on the dataset limitation.
germayne: Yeah? Right? But the idea is that you split the data, you do EDA, you start processing the data, and then what you have is you need to choose the algo.
germayne: Right, and you have all the different parameters. Scikit-learn will have all the parameters for you, so, like, for example, your KNN, you have your number of neighbors, your distance metric, what kind of metric try and measure for the distance, etc, etc.
germayne: Right? So you can see here, it says that the whole data set is trained, the model. So this is the one that I talked about, sorry.
germayne: this was the one that I talked about just now, where after you do K4, right, you can also choose to use the full training dataset. It is a valid strategy, right?
germayne: And you can use the same parameter that you found previously, right? Then after that, you do the evaluation on the test.
germayne: Actually, this one, I think they are talking about one single test.
germayne: Okay? So, just keep this in mind. This is usually the gold standard, in my opinion.
germayne: Okay, lah, I don't think we really have time. We will have to shift the… we will have to shift the… On Saturday, right, we'll go through, one…
germayne: 2… 3… okay, we'll go through 3 new models. So what this means is that when you guys start the Kaggle, you guys will have
germayne: I want you guys to use up to 3.1 to 3.4, okay, for Kaggle, like, nothing, nothing beyond.
germayne: Right, we make the scope smaller. So 3.1 to 3.4, everything is… and okay, it must have integrity lah, there's no way I can test what you guys are…
germayne: what you guys are using, but 3.1 to 3.4 will unlock everything that you need to do the full model training workflow that we'll go through on Saturday. Okay, so I think we sort of…
germayne: Covered, like, half of this.
germayne: we will… we'll spend some time on Saturday to finish up the notebooks lah, right? Soon we'll go through the notebooks on Saturday.
germayne: Yeah. Okay, I hope that you guys get… okay, what I'll do is I'll send the draft that I drew today with the other thing lah, okay? I'll just give you guys… so, if you guys feel like maybe you want to follow from your video, I think you guys can have the option. So I'll share that with you guys.
germayne: Okay? So, I think these are the most important concepts, really. I think for subsequent lessons, if there are things that I think is not relevant, I will choose to exclude it, but I think for all this, it's really the basic foundation. So, you guys really, really need to spend time to understand this.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so I think we've still got time. Anybody got any last questions so far, at this point?
germayne: Or actually, conceptually, it makes sense.
germayne: All good.
germayne: Okay, fantastic.
germayne: Yeah, so Saturday we'll introduce 3 more models. Three more models that are a bit more flexible, right? Which means that they are actually much better than linear regression for prediction.
germayne: And what you guys can do is you guys can then try out
germayne: In the Kaggle to see, and you guys will start to realize that actually some models are really very good. Like, some models are really just so much better than other models, yeah.
germayne: Okay, no question? No question? All good? Okay, I'll share the… let's do the survey, then I think we can call your day lah.
germayne: 3.4.
germayne: Yep.
germayne: Oh.
germayne: Okay, so for today, is this the first question?
germayne: Sorry, sorry. What do you, what do you guys learn today?
germayne: What's the takeaway from today?
germayne: So, as you guys are writing, right, I'll just narrate more, more, more things about the SKLearn library. So, what's the motivation of using the pipeline? Actually, if you use the pipeline, right, it will integrate very, very nicely with the cross-validation. So they have, like, some cross-validation module where
germayne: You just need to put in the pipeline, and then they will just do everything for you behind the scenes. So that's the benefit of doing SKLearn. But the drawback, again, is that because everything is, like.
germayne: a rep into this pipeline, right? You cannot control
germayne: Right, so for example, in my use case, I might want to split the validation to do some stuff in between. So, what I typically do, and a lot of people in the industry, is that you usually write a for loop to just do the K4 manually. You just do a for loop, just a for loop.
germayne: Right? Or we can just spareolarize. But, yeah, that's the motivation for the thing.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, so, so basically, yeah, I think validation is a good takeaway. We talk a bit more than validation, yeah, we talk about the regularization also.
germayne: Hey, but you guys seem to forget about the virus variants trade-off.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Yeah, actually, there's a lot of nuance I just don't have time to talk about. There's also some nuance on…
germayne: The scaling of the parameter, and actually it will affect your regression when it's regularized.
germayne: We also don't have time to talk about it. We'll see, like, we'll see if Saturday we got spare time. I'll just maybe talk about some small new ones.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, so I think you can see it's a lot of topic, for today. I think it will start to ramp up… it will start to ramp…
germayne: It should be better lah, but every week, actually, there's quite a lot of stuff.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, okay, but yeah.
germayne: Okay, so which one do you guys think is the… is the most challenging today, actually? Which part is actually the… do you find it the hardest?
germayne: I think validation, maybe you guys might think quite intuitive, right?
germayne: the manifa.
germayne: Hey, you know, I can tell you this is not the full… I haven't exposed the full power yet. This one is only, like… this one is only, like, a bit only, you know, just saying, really, really. Haven't, haven't… haven't go all out yet on the map. I think we'll have more later on.
germayne: Hey, but I'm curious though, does people like the math, or people don't like… don't like.
germayne: But then, do you guys feel that if without the math, there's a logic jump? Do you guys feel that way?
germayne: So some instructors, they were like, okay, the thing is just like that.
germayne: But would you be curious to know, like, why it's like that, or do you guys, you guys just feel like, okay, you just tell me the properties, I'm done?
germayne: I don't need to know, like, oh, the math says it's like that.
Teng Lee LIM: I think I'm laughing out.
Zac Ang: really helps.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Does that help, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, it may not be… it may not… not to the point of the derivation of it, but more to, like… Intuition. Put the… put the… because it helps the intuition with…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You know, like, we talk about alpha and beta…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the control, you know? Then you know what are the… what are the levers you have, you know?
germayne: Yes, ma'am.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: seems to be able to describe it better than words. Sometimes words are very hard to write. I mean, right? Then, we start that part. All the different…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: discrete.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: things all in one equation, that… that, you know, intuitively, you know, okay, I'll do this, then what I do, then I do this, what do I do? No, it's like science, federal race law, you know, like, the finger, you know.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Then you know, like, oh, you know one… you don't affect the other, then you know what you're…
germayne: Understand, understand, understand. Okay, okay.
germayne: I'll take that.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Right now, when you talk about your validation and everything, I can understand it, but I just cannot…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I feel that there's a lot of things to gel together, and it's not gelling, you know?
germayne: You need to try out.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Please.
germayne: Correct, correct, correct. At the end, I will do a… at the end, we'll do a mind map lah, don't worry, at the end, we'll do a mind map, but to apply, I think you guys need to try out.
germayne: Yeah. But okay, okay, I take, I take the, I take the direction that math is…
germayne: it… those that understand… okay, so I think it's very simple, right? If you appreciate it, then you use it. If you feel like you don't want it, then I think just… just ignore it.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I agree. It's like, if you appreciate it, then you'll use it. If you don't, then…
germayne: Denny's just…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That's another burden, huh?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: another burden, like, oh, what is this? Like, see early, then you tighten early, then, like, it's a burden, lah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, but I won't… But I realized after these two lessons, like.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Metric is very important, wow, it's like…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: He's not on the model, man.
germayne: Yes, so, again, right, while people are typing, the unfortunate thing is that the model is really the least percentage of work that people do as a data scientist.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: metrics there. I just realized, like, whoa.
germayne: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Aw, No, I'll be like…
germayne: So even, like, all the people, you might think, like, every day we train models. Actually, I can tell you 99% is all on the data pipelines, which is why I teach data pipelines, right? Not 99%, at least, like, 70% is on that.
germayne: 20% is on the thinking, writing the problem, EDA, maybe 1-2% is train model, yeah.
germayne: Yeah, so unfortunately, the model is really just a small component lah, yeah.
germayne: Okay, so how is today?
germayne: Yeah, I think we have a lot of things to do on Saturday, unfortunately.
germayne: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I don't know.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I, I…
germayne: No, lah, I think… I think it's hard to balance lah, because we are trying to squeeze… we're trying to squeeze, like, concepts that are taught in… just telling you guys, right, there are so many concepts that are actually split across. So, like, let's say later you want to learn machine learning, it's like a module itself. You can take, like, some Stanford, you can take Andrew Erg's machine learning specialization.
germayne: you realize it's just a module on his own. Then later on, one more week, we are teaching things like Time Series. Time series has a textbook. I'll be using some textbook to show you guys. Then NLP, you guys know NLP, you can also take a course from Stanford. Deep Learning, again, is another module. Essentially, we are trying to squeeze, like.
germayne: a lot of content-rich items, so that's why I think content is, you know, way too much, I think, to condense.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, I think so far good lah. We just need to buck up a bit more on Saturday, I think. I think it should be okay lah. We should have some time, I think. I think no pressure for soon lah. I think you have the Saturday to catch up on the notebooks, yeah.
germayne: Okay, so what do you think today is the Eureka moment for you guys? Like, what do you enjoy today? Like, what went well for today?
germayne: Hmm.
germayne: Yeah, so I really give you guys a lot of hints for the… the keg already, so hopefully you guys can do well.
germayne: Okay, so I think in the meantime, while you guys are writing, right, what you guys can do is, in your free time, right, just try to sign up for the Kaggle account. You can actually use your Google login.
germayne: Or, I think can log in with some other email. So, in the meantime, right, if you have time, just try to do that, because on Saturday, we'll go through all the lesson, then at the end, right, I need you guys to all link up as a group. I think you can come together as a group, and submit as a group, yeah? Then I need to see whether it works. If not, then I need to go and change some stuff.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, so I hope, I hope that, I think now the story becomes better, because I think, 3.3, we have a lot of, like, hey, shit, you know, like, then everything ended up in 3.4, so… yeah.
germayne: Okay, but it's good lah. I mean, I'm happy that the math helped, because for me, that's how I understand it. Like, I need the math. I cannot do it without the math, so hopefully that is helpful for some of you guys.
germayne: Okay, so what do you think is areas that you'll want to improve on for today?
germayne: Yeah, I will share the… I will share the… the notes in the drive. I'll just dump it, I'll just dump it in. I think maybe what I'll do is I'll create a separate folder, so that those with annotation, you guys can separate it, then those of you can keep the ones without annotation. I'll just put it in a separate folder.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Mmm.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, we will… I mean, use the Kaggle to play lah. I mean, then that would be the best. Then we can at least see the leaderboard.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay? I really think after the Kaggle, we'll run it through the rest of the class.
germayne: Right, we'll run it through, then we'll continue to work on it, and then we will probably use any free time at the back to do some presentation for the teams that did very well.
germayne: Okay? No pressure, lah, no pressure. Yeah, it will be a good one. Okay? So I think that's, that's, that's all.
germayne: So, I think that's all for today. So Saturday, we will just continue with the… with the notebook, and I will also continue with the lecture.
germayne: then, yeah, I think let's try to finish the… we'll try to finish, lah, 3.4.
germayne: by Saturday. I think we should have time.
germayne: Right, then we leave a bit of time at the back to set up the teams in Kaggle.
germayne: Okay, I think that's all. Yeah, thanks everyone, good night, have a good night.
Easwaran Jayaraman: I mean?
germayne: If you guys have any questions, can stay, yeah?
Zac Ang: Thank you.
germayne: Thank you so much, yep, bye-bye.
Edwin Yap: Just a quick one, so, you can ask CP for the videos, I think, for the 3.3 and 3.4, right? Because I think this tool was the most intense, so maybe if we can have the video…
Edwin Yap: It's a good… at least we can go through your draft as well, so yeah, a good, deeper understanding, mah.
CP Wong: Yeah, everyone in CP here. So, I'll be uploading the videos tomorrow, usually on Fridays and Saturdays, so just look out for it.
Edwin Yap: Oh, oh, thanks, I didn't know that. Oh, Feng also in… CP is also in…
CP Wong: Because of you lah, you come down here.
Edwin Yap: That's what you… Okay, thanks, my answer, my calls are answered, thank you.
CP Wong: Okay, okay, okay. Okay, don't stress too much lah, go on, Steve,
germayne: Okay. Okay, good night, good night. Good guys. Good night.
CP Wong: Woi.
CP Wong: Okay, let's stop the recording.
CP Wong: Who's the…
germayne: Maybe I stopped, I stop.